-Hello? -Sonny, it's your dad You asleep?
- 你好? - Sonny,我是爸爸,你在睡觉?
No. Hey, man. I was exercising.
不,不,我在…锻炼
-Bullshit You were sleeping -I wasn't.
- 胡扯,你是在睡觉 - 不,我没有
This kid won't stop lying to me You still act like you're six
你总是向我撒谎 好像你还是六岁小孩
Yeah, okay, Dad I act like I'm six
噢,好吧,爸,我像六岁小孩
Found a job yet, where you work more than one day a week?
你找到个像样的工作了吗?
I've been looking
正在找呢
Looking won't pay the rent
"找"可付不了房租
All the money I won from the cab accident
我从那场出租车意外中得到的赔偿
is kicking ass in the stock market, so relax
都投资股市了,放心
-Don't blow it on worthless crap -I won't
- 不要浪费了 - 我不会的
You should spend it on your bar exam
你该把钱用在你的律师考试上
You're the lawyer I ain't taking a bar exam
你是个律师,我可不想考什么律师
I got too much other shit going on
我自己还有太多其它事要烦
I don't know what happened to you
我真不知道你到底是怎么了
How're things going with your girlfriend, Vanessa?
算了,你和那女孩怎么样了,Vanessa?
Things are going fine.
一切都好
Shit!
糟糕!
I gotta go.
我得挂了
Shit! You turned off the alarm clock again.
该死!你又把闹钟关了
No! I mean, yes, I did, but I thought you needed more sleep.
不!我是考虑到你需要更多睡眠
I shouldn't have stayed here. That was a jerk thing to do.
我根本就不该留在这儿 太蠢了,真是多谢了!
Why are you going to work? It's Sunday.
你干嘛,为什么要去上班? 今天是周日
I'm not going to work. I'm going to brunch with potential clients.
我不是去上班,我要和潜在的客户 吃早中饭
That's how a party planner gets business, by making contacts.
作为晚会策划者,就得这样 多和客户见面
Meet with me. I'll order in from Cozy's. We'll have fun.
和我见面好了,我来叫 Cozy's 的外卖 那多开心
I am sick of Cozy's. You order in from there all the time.
我讨厌 Cozy's 你总是从那儿叫东西吃
The delivery guy's your best friend.
那送外卖的看上去 就是你最好的朋友了
He happens to be pretty damn nice.
他人确实不错
This is a rough patch in my life.
这是我人生的低潮期
Syracuse is 0 and 3. And I got those medical problems.
雪城0比3输了 而我又有那些医疗问题
Medical problems?
医疗问题?
A cab runs over your foot two years ago. You're hospitalized one night.
两年前被出租车轧了脚 你就住了一天医院
First of all, that cab was huge.
注意,那辆出租车可很大
And a jury decided that one night of pain was worth $200,000.
而且陪审团认为那一晚上的疼痛 值20万美元
-So there you go. -Whatever.
- 你还能说什么 - 随便吧
Why are you being so nuts to me lately?
你怎么了?为什么最近这么疙瘩?
You refuse to move on to the next phase.
因为,是你拒绝让我们 发展到下个阶段
I'd like to have a family someday.
我希望某天能有自己的家庭
I need someone I can rely on, not a playmate.
但我需要的是一个我能依赖的人 不是玩伴
You need a father figure? "Stop pulling your sister's hair!"
难道你需要一个父亲的形象? "不要拉你妹妹的头发!"
You know what? I'm gonna go to Syracuse to see my mom.
知道吗?我要去雪城看我妈
-I'll be back on Wednesday. -What are you talking about?
- 我周三回来 - 等等,你在说什么?
I had call for delivery, but it was crank call. You want chocolate cake?
有人打电话叫了外卖又不收 巧克力蛋糕,你要吗?
Come back later. I'll lndian wrestle you.
你来的不是时候,来晚点儿吧 到时跟你玩扳推
You're going down, sucker.
你输定了,兄弟
We'll see about that.
到时候再看
Okay. Peace, out.
好,我走了
You're going to Syracuse?
你说要去雪城是什么意思?
I need time to think and so do you.
我需要时间考虑,你也一样
Think about what?
思考什么?
Your life and why I should be a part of it.
你的生活还有我为什么 要成为当中的一部分
All right.
好吧
While you're at it, think about getting a real job.
考虑的时候 不如也考虑找个真正的工作
I got a real job!
我有真正的工作!
Patrick Ewing, nice shot.
帕特里克·尤因,好球
-Hey, Sonny. -What's up, buddy boy?
- 嘿,Sonny - 你好吗,伙计
I'm out the door. Hey, pal.
我走了,嘿,伙计
-Where you going? -Manhattan.
- 你要去哪? - 曼哈顿
You wanna take me with you?
愿意带我一程吗?
All right, I guess.
我想可以
Hold onto your money. Later on.
好,钱收起来吧,回见
Okay, take care, Sonny.
好,保重,Sonny
See you.
再见
Cadillac, I love it.
凯迪拉克,我喜欢
Surprise!
惊喜!
Just ignore him.
不是他
It's only Sonny. It's only Sonny.
不过是 Sonny,不过是 Sonny
Yeah, it's only me. It's only me.
对,不过是我,不过是我
-What's going on? -Corinne's going-away party for Kevin.
- 要干嘛? - Corinne 给Kevin 举办的告别晚会
She didn't tell me. The roommate has a right to know.
她为什么不告诉我? 室友有权知道啊
She knew you'd ruin the surprise.
她认为你告诉了他就不是惊喜了
No, I wouldn't.
不,我不会的
Hey, surprise.
嘿,惊喜吧
Surprise.
惊喜
What's going on?
怎么了?
We wasted the good surprise on you.
我们把惊喜浪费在你身上了
All right.
没错
Is this your handiwork?
你的杰作吧?
I guess.
估计是
See you in three hours.
3小时后见
Good to see you stiffs. What've you been doing?
很高兴见到你们 你最近在干什么?
Last three weeks have been crazy. I've been in Denver, Dallas--
最近三周真是疯狂 我去了丹佛,达拉斯
I'm sleeping in the office. We're going to trial on the fraud case.
我在办公室睡大觉 我们在做一宗欺诈案
Honey, it was a great surprise. I was totally shocked.
宝贝,我真的很惊喜 我彻底被震住了
No, you weren't! And I worked so hard on this.
不,你没有! 而我费了那么大劲准备
Need some help?
要我帮忙吗?
-Honey, your sister's here. -Hey, sweetie.
- 宝贝,你妹妹来了 - 嘿,甜心
I hate Sonny.
我恨 Sonny
My client's out $7 million. All we can sue on is breach of contract.
我的客户损失了7百万 而我们只能告对方违约
Maybe you can sue under the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act.
或许你可以依据《反海外腐败法》起诉
I gotta get back to the office. You're the king.
我得回办公室一趟 你真了不起
Mikey, a pleasure.
Mikey,很荣幸
-I'll see you at home. -All right.
- 回家见 - 好的
I'll walk you out.
我送你出去
I gotta admit, I'm still weirded out when they kiss.
我得承认,这个吻让我感觉很不舒服
Why? They're gay. That's what gay guys do.
为什么?他们是同性恋 他们这样很正常
I know, but they were like brothers to us back in school.
我知道,但在学校的时候 他们看上去就像兄弟
They're still like our brothers. Our very, very gay brothers.
他们仍然像我们的兄弟 我们非常非常同性恋的兄弟
What are you doing after this? Going to a Klan meeting?
你一会去哪?参加3K党集会?
Remember when Dad had that barbecue for his friends and it rained...
还记不记得爸爸那次 为他朋友烧烤的时候突然下雨…
...so he and Mom went into the kitchen and made...
…然后他就和妈妈在厨房里…
...1 00 hamburgers with one frying pan?
…用一个煎锅做了100个汉堡?
You're not gonna let a little rain stop you from making 1 00 hamburgers.
你不会让一点小雨 阻止你做100个汉堡吧
That relationship's lasted longer than I thought it would.
他们的关系比我想象的持续得久
Look at his eyes. He's bored. I give it two more weeks.
看他的眼神,他已经厌了 也就再有两个礼拜
Hey, excuse me. Everybody!
嘿,不好意思,各位!
I'm sorry. I wanted to thank you for coming tonight.
我很抱歉,我要谢谢你们今晚前来
I guess I should say--
我想我该说…
I'm getting it.
我正在学
Tomorrow I'm leaving for China to represent the firm of Morton and Mandel.
明天我要代表 Morton&Mandel 公司去中国
Me, the same guy who once shaved his ass to win a $5 bet.
我,曾经为了赌5美元而刮屁股的家伙
Prove it!
证明一下!
Just kidding.
开个玩笑
But I am real glad you're all here tonight, because...
我真的很高兴今晚你们都来了 因为…
...l'm gonna do what I never thought I'd have the guts to do.
我要做一件我从来没敢做的事
You're not proposing, are you?
你难道要求婚?
Yeah, pal, I am.
对,兄弟,是的
Well, think about it, you know?
喔,考虑考虑,明白吗?
God, Sonny, shut up!
老天,Sonny,闭嘴!
Anyway, will you?
不管了,你愿意吗?
Yeah.
愿意
Good call on the two weeks.
你还说两周
Sonny, what was that all about?
Sonny,刚才为什么那样说?
Congratulations. You and " Big Boobs" McGee are gonna be happy.
恭喜,你和"波霸" McGee会 很幸福的
Don't call her that.
别这样称呼她
You wanna tell your children you met their mother as a waitress at Hooters?
你想告诉你的孩子们 他们的妈妈是 Hooters 餐厅的舞女?
Sonny, that was five years ago. She's a doctor now...
Sonny,那是5年前的事了 她现在是个医生
...and my fianc閑, so from now on...
并且是我的未婚妻 所以从现在起
...Dr. Big Boobs McGee.
是波霸 McGee 医生
-Congratulations. -Thanks, man.
- 恭喜 - 多谢,兄弟
I just...
我只是
...got shit going on.
最近不太顺利
What's the matter?
怎么了?
Vanessa's gonna break up with me...
Vanessa 要和我分手
...and I don't know how to make her wanna stay.
而且我不知道怎样留住她
She's getting older. She wants different things:
那是因为她长大了 她想要不同的东西了…
Career, stable relationship, a family.
事业,稳定的关系,家庭
That's how they get.
那是她们需要的
I want things to go back to the way they used to be.
我只是想事情回到以前的样子
When we were at Syracuse, and Vanessa worshiped you.
就像我们在雪城,Vanessa 仰慕你
-That was nice. -Nobody hassled you to get a job.
- 那真好 - 也没人催你找工作
Tommy and Phil showered separately.
Tommy 和Phil 还分开洗澡
Those were the days.
就是那段时光
-What're you doing? -If I make this...
- 你要干嘛? - 如果我打成这杆
...Vanessa will realize she likes me the way I am.
Vanessa 会意识到她喜欢的是 现在的我
You're going to the putt.
你要打进洞
Remember, the roof breaks to the right.
别忘了,这屋顶有点向右倾斜
Yes! That's what I'm talk--
进了! 这正是我所说的…
Good God!
老天!
That can't be good.
这可不好
Where's Kevin?
Kevin 呢?
He already left. I guess he forgot to say goodbye to you.
已经走了,他大概忘了跟你说再见了
-Why are you here? -I'm cleaning because you're useless.
- 你为什么还在这儿? - 我在清扫,不能指望你
Then what, you gonna go to your Hooters reunion?
然后呢? 去找你们那些 Hooters 餐厅的舞女?
You guys talk about whose ass hangs out of their shorts the most?
你们是不是会讨论谁的屁股最容易 从短裤里露出来?
At least I can fit my ass in my shorts, fatty.
至少我能把屁股塞进短裤,肥佬
Speaking of fatty, whose is this?
说到肥佬,这个是谁的?
-I don't know. -I'm eating it then.
- 不知道 - 那我就吃了它
"We wasted the good surprise on you."
"我们把惊喜浪费在你身上了"
Lady gave me $5 to bring him here.
有位女士给我5美元让我带他来这儿
-What do you mean? -Later.
- 什么意思? - 再见
Are you selling raffle tickets?
你们是卖彩票的?
Oh, boy.
噢,兄弟
-Kevin Gerrity. -I got something to tell you
- Kevin Gerrity - 是我,有事要告诉你
What's up?
什么事?
There's a kid here.
这儿有个小孩
What kind of kid?
什么样的小孩?
If this note is true, it's your kid.
如果这字条是真的,那他就是你的小孩
What do you mean?
你在说什么?
I'm having a tough time reading this...
我不想读这个
...but it says, " Dear Kevin: This is Julian, your son.
但上面说,"亲爱的 Kevin 这是 Julian,你的儿子"
I hope you understand why I didn't tell you until now...
"我希望你能理解为什么 现在才告诉你"
but he needs your help I can't be his mother anymore "
"但他需要你的帮助 我不能再做他的母亲了"
-This is ridiculous. -Hang on
- 这真荒谬 - 等等
Who's this?
这是谁?
This is my friend.
这是我朋友
-Is that Kevin on the phone? -No, it's my Uncle Remus.
- 你在和 Kevin 通电话? - 不,是我叔叔 Remus
What's your name?
Hi,你叫什么?
Is he all right?
他没事吧?
He doesn't like you. Leave us alone.
他只是不喜欢你,离我们远点
You're such a dick.
你个垃圾
That was your girlfriend. She was acting " Hooterific."
是你女朋友,她表现得很"舞女"
Who sent that note?
字条是谁送的?
"Jan."
"Jan"
Jan.... I don't know any Jan.
Jan?我不认识什么 Jan
-Where's he from? -Where are you from?
- 他从哪儿来? - 你从哪来,兄弟?
Buffalo.
水牛城
I've never even been to Buffalo.
水牛城,我从来没去过水牛城! 有人在整我
Maybe it's a mistake.
也许是搞错了
Is this like the time you said my parents were dead?
行了,真有个小孩? 还是你想绕圈子告诉我我父母去世了?
I swear, he's right here.
我发誓,他就在这儿
I'm coming home. I don't know what I'll say--
我马上回来,我不知道该说什么…
Hang on. It says...
不,等等,这上面说
..." If you won't take responsibility for him, they found a foster family--"
"如果你不想负责,那就找人领养他…"
Yes, Uncle Remus, I know the catfish are huge.
是的,Remus 叔叔 我知道那鲶鱼很大
That's terrific
太棒了
Here's a number for a guy...
这里有个号码
at City Social Service Arthur Brooks I'll call
是市社会服务处的 叫 Arthur Brooks 我来打给他
-I'll come home -I'll take care of it.
- 我还是回来吧 - 不不,我来处理吧
Are you sure?
你确定能搞定?
Yeah, don't worry.
是的,会处理好的,放心
Hooters. Hooters. Hooters!
舞女,舞女,舞女!
-All right. Thanks a lot. -Later
- 那好,多谢了 - 那就这样
I'm gonna make another phone call.
我要再打个电话
You want to come and sit down, pal?
你要过来坐吗,伙计?
Or you can stand there. Anything you want. I'll be a minute.
或者你就站那儿 随便你,我很快就好
Social Services is closed today, Columbus Day
社会服务处休息 今天是哥伦布纪念日
We'll be open tomorrow at 8 am
我们明早8点恢复服务
Columbus Day.
哥伦布纪念日
Boy, I don't know what to tell you.
孩子,我不知道怎么跟你说
Everything's gonna get figured out tomorrow.
别担心,明天早上一切都会好的
Can you be a tough little guy until then?
在这之前,你能当个坚强的小家伙吗?
Great.
很好
Do I need to get you a bottle of formula or something?
要我给你弄个奶瓶还是什么的吗?
What do you eat?
你吃什么?
Food.
食物
Yeah? I eat food too.
真的?我也吃食物
What--? Come on.
怎么…?过来啊
You need me to hold your hand?
要我牵着你?
On Mondays, I go to Central Park and watch rollerbladers fall down.
周一我没事都去中央公园 看滑轮滑的人摔跟头
-You into that? -I don't know.
- 你想去吗? - 不知道
Watch. This guy's humming.
看着,这家伙磕磕绊绊
He's going down, he's going down, he's going--!
他要摔了,他要摔了,他要…!
How old are you, anyways?
那么,你几岁了?
Five.
5岁
You wear a diaper?
你穿纸尿布吗?
You wipe your own ass then?
那你是自己擦屁股喽?
You do? Good job. That's cool.
真的?不错,很酷
Come on, fall down. Fall down. Yes! Come on, damn it.
快,摔倒摔倒 对了!噢,快,该死
You suck. You suck!
你不行,你不行!
Check this out.
瞧好了
My God!
我的天!
There's a stick there. Somebody should move it.
那儿有根棍子,应该有人拿掉它
All right now, what way would you put that on?
好了,你要把它放那儿?
This Columbo, he pretends to be stupid...
这是 Columbo,他假装很蠢
...but he's really smart as a tack.
但他其实很聪明
Oh, yeah, he is.
喔,对,是的
You put the vane on down there Then this boat comes up
你把桨叶放下去,船就会上来了
I wipe my own ass.
我自己擦屁股
Me too.
我也是
So, Mr. Ass Wiper, what's this guy's name?
那么擦屁股先生,这家伙是谁?
Scuba Steve.
Scuba Steve
Does he ever take his flippers off?
我喜欢那脚蹼,他一直穿着吗?
What if he goes bowling?
他打保龄球的时候呢?
They don't make him wear bowling shoes? He wears flippers?
他们不会让他换保龄球鞋? 他还穿脚蹼?
Really?
- 对 - 真的?
I had a doll like that at one time.
我以前也有这样一个娃娃
But my cat, he bite his head off.
但我的猫,把他头咬掉了
What cat would do that?
什么猫会这样?
You calling me a liar?
你说我在撒谎?
Hey, take it easy.
嘿,放松
Anyways...
不管了
...Jets are playing tonight.
今晚有 Jets 队的比赛
We're gonna go to the Blarney Stone. Wanna come?
我们去 Blarney Stone 看球 你要来吗?
I've got more deliveries.
我还有很多外卖要送
Maybe you can also finish the turkey on your lip.
或许你该先把嘴上的火鸡吃干净
Right there.
就是那儿
Let's crank up the Styx
来点 Styx 的音乐
No music during the game.
比赛时不要放音乐
-It's halftime. Relax, Mr. Herlihy. -Goddamn Jets.
- 中场休息,放松,Herlihy 先生 - 该死的 Jets 队
What are you doing in here, cutie?
你来这儿干嘛,小可爱?
Watching football.
看橄榄球
-Who do you want to win? -The goddamn Jets.
- 你希望谁赢? - 该死的 Jets 队
Have fun.
玩开心点
Too bad you don't like girls. I think you could've had her.
可惜你不喜欢泡妞 我认为你能钓到她
-I'm thirsty. -You're thirsty?
- 我渴 - 你渴了?
Are you allowed soda?
要什么?你能喝苏打水吗?
I don't know.
不知道
My mom always said soda rots your teeth...
我妈总是说喝苏打水会蛀牙
...but you'll lose them anyway, so rot on.
但你总要换牙的,所以蛀就蛀吧,对吧
-Can we get two root beers? -Sure.
- 给我们来两杯苏打水? - 好的
When I graduated law school, we met here every Monday to watch football.
刚从法律学校毕业的时候,我们 每周一都来这儿看球
Who would meet you?
谁和你一起?
My friends, Vanessa.
我女朋友,Vanessa
Vanessa always rooted against the team I wanted to win just to bust my chops.
Vanessa 总是反对我喜欢的球队 让我难堪
But everybody's so busy with their crap lately, no one comes.
但现在每个人都在忙自己的事 都不过来了
Like I'm not busy?
你是说我不忙?
Shut up or I'll smack you through the wall like last Monday.
闭嘴,否则我像上周一样把你扔到墙上
Last Monday was a fluke. Bring it on, woman.
上周是你侥幸,来啊,娘们
Anytime.
随时恭候
He drinks a lot of soda.
他喝了太多苏打水
I'm telling you, buddy. Vanessa, she's the one. I can't lose her.
我跟你说,兄弟,Vanessa 她就是我的挚爱,我不能失去她
I'm not getting any handsomer.
我不会变得更帅了
Every day I get a little bit older and balder and fatter.
每天我都在一点点变老变秃变肥
Fatter?
变肥?
At your age I could eat anything. Wouldn't gain an ounce.
是啊,我像你这么大的时候 什么都能吃却不会增重
Now, I have a chocolate shake, my ass jiggles for a week.
而现在,吃块巧克力 我屁股上的肥肉就能晃一星期
-Enjoy the metabolism while you got it. -Metalobism?
- 趁你新陈代谢还正常,好好享受吧 - 新陈代谢?
Good God, it's 2:30 in the morning. You must be wrecked.
老天,已经凌晨2:30了 你是不是吃了兴奋剂
Anyways, I had fun today. Did you have fun?
不管怎么说,我今天挺开心 你开心吗?
Yeah, you're all right.
好,很不错
Have a good one.
做个好梦
Could I have a night-light?
能给我开盏夜灯吗?
Night-light? I think I can help you out. Hang on.
夜灯?我想可以,等等
Let's see here.
试试看(现场脱衣舞)
There you go, all right?
好了,行吗?
Are you my dad?
Sonny,你是我爸爸吗?
No, I'm not, but...
不,我不是,不过
...that Dad and Mom thing we'll figure out in the morning.
爸爸妈妈的事早上我们会弄清楚的 好吗?
You just go to sleep.
你乖乖睡觉吧
-Good night.
- 晚安
Go get the can, okay?
去把罐子捡回来,好吗?
Go! Go! Go!
上!上!上!
I'm thinking about keeping the kid.
我在考虑把这孩子留下
Remember when we went to the pet store...
记得我们一起去宠物店
...and you wanted that puppy, but I reminded you about feeding it...
你想要那条小狗 但我提醒你以后要喂它
...cleaning it and toilet training it?
给它洗澡,还要训练它上厕所?
This is kind of like that, except with a human.
这和那差不多,只不过是个人
I mean, I'm glad you had fun and all, but this is big.
我的意思是,我很高兴你这么开心 不过这不是小事
I gotta do something big. I think Vanessa will respect that.
我是要做点大事 我想 Vanessa 会对我肃然起敬的
You think that since women get pregnant to fix a troubled relationship...
你是不是认为既然女人可以 靠怀孕来挽救关系
...why can't a guy adopt a kid to do the same?
为什么男人不能通过收养小孩 达到同样目的?
I didn't think of it like that. But yes, that's what I'm thinking.
我不是那样想的 不过,对,我是想达到这个目的
Sounds nuts to me, pal. Do yourself a favour. Sleep on it.
听上去你是疯了,伙计 为你自己着想,好好考虑再决定
You're right. Can I use your phone?
你说的对,用一下你手机?
Arthur Brooks speaking.
你好,我是 Arthur Brooks
How you doing? Kevin Gerrity.
嘿,你好 Brooks 先生 我是 Kevin Gerrity
Right on, Mr Gerrity
啊,正好,Gerrity 先生
We were expecting you.
我们正在等你的电话
Do you still got a foster family lined up for Julian?
你们那儿有等着领养 Julian 的家庭吗?
Yes, we do.
有啊
I've decided to take care of the little guy.
你可以让他们放弃了 我决定照顾这小家伙了
Way to sleep on it, pal.
你还没好好考虑,伙计
You two want to get married, I support that.
你们俩要结婚我都支持了 就别管我了
When parents take the responsibility, there's no bigger high for us.
如果亲生父母想要回他 我们其他人就无权阻止了
I'm psyched about it too
我也很希望这样
So that's it.
那就这么说了
Yep. Good luck to you and your son.
好,就这样,祝你和你儿子好运
My son.
我的儿子
Goddamn stick!
该死的棍子!
That's my boy.
这才是我的孩子
Go back to sleep.
回去睡觉
Well, I'm going back to sleep. Nighty-night.
好吧,我要睡觉了,晚安
I wet my bed.
我尿床了
Oh, God.
哦,天呐
That's a shitload of piss.
好大一坨呐
There you go, all right?
这样好了吧?
No more wetness.
不会湿了
Sleep, all right? Just try to sleep. Stay asleep.
睡吧,好吗?好好睡着,多睡会儿
Sit still!
不要乱动!
Lay!
躺好!
All right! I'm up!
好了!我起床!
It smells like urine in this joint. Good job.
整个房子里都是尿味儿,干得好
What're you doing there, boy?
你在干嘛,孩子?
Making cereal.
做麦片
Oh, yeah? Why don't you pour me a bowl?
哦,是吗?何不给我也倒一碗?
Or don't pour me a bowl. Either way.
或者不要给我倒,随便
I got it. I got it.
我来,我来
We can fix this.
我来收拾好
It's not a big deal.
这没什么大不了
Look. See?
看,看见吗?
See how quick it goes away?
这么快就没了
Crybaby, come on.
哭吧,宝贝,快
Don't worry about it, boy.
不用担心,孩子
Scuba Steve, damn you!
Scuba Steve,你这该死的!
You think that's funny, me getting hurt?
你认为这好笑,我这么痛苦?
There's a bright side to being up before 1 1 : McDonald's breakfast.
11点前起来有个好处,就是我们能赶上 麦当劳的早餐
I haven't been up for that in 1 0 years. You wanna go?
我有10年没去吃了,你想去吗?
Tie your shoes, we'll go. Hurry.
系好鞋带,我们走,要快点了
It's like 1 2 blocks from here, so tie quickly.
离这儿有12个街区,所以快点系
Do you need help with that?
要帮忙吗?
I can do it.
我可以的
Let me do it.
还是我来吧
You loop it, you swoop it and you pull.
绕一下,穿进去,拉
Good. Let's go. We're in a hurry.
好,走吧,我们得快点
It's different for your generation.
你们这一代不同了
You've always had McDonald's breakfast available.
总是有麦当劳早餐可以吃
I have?
是吗?
When I was born, all we had were the burgers and fries.
我出生那会儿,只有汉堡和炸鸡
Maybe the fish sandwich. I'm not sure. I'll get back to you.
好像还有鱼三明治,我不确定 我得仔细回忆
What are you doing?
你要干嘛?
Oh, yeah, the hand-holding thing.
哦,对,牵手的事
My dad took us to McDonald's the first morning they had breakfast.
我爸吃过早餐后带我们去麦当劳
Everybody was baffled. "Are these sausages or hamburgers?"
大家去后都很诧异 "这到底是香肠还是汉堡?"
I have to go to the bathroom.
我要上厕所
We're gonna be there in a minute.
我们很快就到了
I gotta go now.
我憋不住了
Didn't you pee enough in bed?
你在床上还没尿够?
We only got nine minutes to get there.
只有9分钟了
But I gotta go to the bathroom.
但我想上厕所
All right, let's go.
好吧,走
Can my kid use the bathroom for a minute?
能让我孩子用一下卫生间吗?
Customers only.
顾客才行
He's just a kid. We'll be in and out.
他只是个孩子,我们很快就出来
That's not my problem.
这不关我的事
It's not your problem? All right.
不关你的事?好吧
Come on.
来吧
Here you are. Your waiter will be right with you.
请坐,随时为您效劳
I can't do it.
我尿不出来
What do you mean, you can't do it? Just go.
什么意思,尿不出来?放心尿
I'm scared. Could you do it too?
我害怕,你能陪我吗?
All right.
好吧
Here we go.
开始吧
And we're off.
出来了
That's not too difficult, right?
不是很难,对吧?
And we're both losing weight.
我们都在减轻重量
Good job. We're gonna miss breakfast. Let's go.
干得好 我们要赶不上早餐了,快走
Put it away.
收起来
-Thanks, anyways. -Sure thing. Anytime.
- 还是谢谢你了 - 没问题,随时效劳
Move your ass there, pee-boy.
快点儿走,小尿包
We only got five minutes, five minutes. Now four.
我们只剩5分钟了,5分钟,现在4分钟了
Come on. We're almost there.
快,我们就到了
Hey, mister. Why are you sitting on the ground?
嘿,先生,你为什么坐在地上?
This is where I live.
我住在这儿
We gotta get going.
我们得走了
Why?
为什么?
In retrospect, I made some bad choices after high school.
回想起来,因为我高中毕业时 做了个错误的选择
-We gotta get going. -Why?
- 我们得走了 - 为什么?
This was during the so-called Disco Era...
那据说是个很好的时代
...but for me, it was more the Doing Mushrooms Era.
但对我来说,那是个很郁闷的时代
-We're gonna miss breakfast. -Why?
- 我们要错过早餐了 - 为什么?
I never thought about that.
我从来没想过
I was never Mr. Popularity in high school...
高中时我一直都不受欢迎
...and I watched Fantasia a lot.
我经常看电视剧
-One day it clicked. -Hey, yappy.
- 有天我醒悟了 - 嘿,流浪汉
If you end it, you get an Egg McMuffin.
如果你结束对话 我就给你个吉士蛋堡
How about a Sausage McMuffin with hash browns?
不如来个火腿汉堡加土豆饼?
You got a deal.
成交
Look, look. He fell asleep. Let's go.
看,看,他睡着了,快走
Sausage McMuffin.
火腿汉堡
Pardon me, sir.
对不起,先生
How you doing?
你好?
What can I get for you?
要点什么?
-What do you want? -Cheerios.
- 你要吃什么? - 麦片
They don't got Cheerios.
这儿没有麦片
Lasagna.
烤饼
What's the matter? We'll take hot cakes and sausage.
你怎么回事?我们要热蛋糕和香肠
Sorry. We stopped serving breakfast.
对不起,我们已经停止供应早餐了
We're four seconds late.
我们只晚了4秒
You're 30 minutes and four seconds late. Breakfast stops at 1 0:30.
你们晚了半小时加4秒 早餐10:30结束
Horseshit!
啊!狗屎!
Don't cry. Sorry.
别哭,对不起
I was cursing at the lady, not you.
我在骂这位女士,不是你
Nice parenting.
好父亲
Thanks. Are you my therapist? Take a walk.
谢谢,你是我的心理医生?走开
Do you want a Happy Meal?
想吃开心乐园餐吗?
You got a Happy Meal?
有开心乐园餐吗?
Will somebody get the kid a Happy Meal?!
谁给我的孩子拿个开心乐园餐?!
Relax.
放松
Where's my Egg McMuffin?
我的吉士蛋堡呢?
Breakfast is over at 1 0:30.
早餐10:30就结束了
-Really? I thought it was 1 1 . -I thought that too.
- 真的?我还以为到11点 - 我也这么以为
Total mind blower.
说话不算数
Will you just relax? Here.
你能不能不要哭了?下来
What do you want me to do?
你想要我怎样?
You're gonna meet Vanessa tonight. You'll like her.
你今晚会见到 Vanessa 她很好,你会喜欢她的
You wanna see me get hurt? That'll cheer you up?
你想看我痛苦吗? 那样是不是会让你高兴?
All right.
好吧
You think that's funny?
喜欢吗?你认为很有趣?
Good. No more crying.
好,不能再哭了
Are you okay?
你没事吧?
Next time, kill me.
下次撞死我
Let's do it, Rangers.
好好干,游骑兵队
--Rangers against the Tampa Bay Lightning
…纽约游骑兵队迎战坦帕湾闪电队
And at this stage
这场比赛
it's as close as you can get to a must-win game for the Rangers
对于纽约游骑兵队来说不能失败
Or they'll fall behind--
否则他们排名会落后…
How you doing?
你在干嘛?
You like hockey?
你喜欢冰球?
This is a big, important game.
这是场非常,重要的比赛
Cut the crap.
不准学
I'm serious. Don't do that.
我是认真的,不要这样
How much wood would a woodchuck chuck, if a woodchuck could chuck wood?
吃葡萄不吐葡萄皮 不吃葡萄倒吐葡萄皮
That's what I thought. Shut up.
这个你不会,闭嘴吧
Don't you take naps?
你从来不休息吗?
Sometimes.
有时
Go take a nap.
那去休息会儿
I'm too hungry to sleep.
我太饿,睡不着
You want some food?
要吃东西吗?
Having a kid is great...
有孩子真好
...as long as his eyes are closed and he's not moving or speaking.
只要他眼睛闭上就不会乱动 也不会说话了
He's taken down! Penalty shot!
他被撞到了!罚球
How you doing? You sleepwalking?
嘿,你在干嘛?你梦游?
Why don't you go back sleepy? Sleepy.
为什么不回去睡觉觉?觉觉
Keep napping. What's this?
再睡会这是什么?
Kangaroo song.
袋鼠歌
That's terrific. And we'll watch this after the game, okay?
太棒了那我们比赛后看,好吗?
But after my nap, I always watch the kangaroo song.
但我每次小睡醒来,都要看袋鼠歌
It's overtime, and there's a penalty shot about to take place.
现在是加时赛,而且马上要罚点球
It happens every 1 0 years--
这是十年难遇的比赛…
Kangaroo song. Kangaroo song!
袋鼠歌袋鼠歌!
All right!
好吧!
God! You were normal yesterday.
老天!你昨天还挺正常的
I can't take this. Are you serious?
我受不了,你真要看这个?
Come and play
来一起玩
What do you say?
你说什么?
Douche-bag kangaroo.
大袋子袋鼠
Are you all hopped out?
怎么了,你跳完了?
I don't know what to do. Hopefully Vanessa will.
我不知道怎么办了 希望 Vanessa 知道
I think she's back. If she's not back, we'll wait for her.
我想她已经回来了 如果她没回来,我们就在她家门口等
Get your coat. Clean up.
去穿上外套,弄干净
Oh, God. You don't have to pee, do you?
噢,老天,你不想小便吧?
-Do you swear? -I swear.
- 你发誓? - 我发誓
How come you're not going?
你为什么不尿?
I don't have to go. Only you and my grandfather go every 30 seconds.
我现在不用尿 就你和我爷爷每30秒要尿一次
Let's hurry it up, all right? I'm keeping you company.
我们动作快点,好吗? 我得在这儿陪着你
He'll write your name on the wall. Mind your business.
他会把你们的名字在墙上尿出来 管好你们自己吧
Let's go. Let's go.
走吧,快走
Why do I need to meet this lady?
我为什么要见这位女士?
-Now it is your problem. -Thank you.
- 现在是你的事了 - 谢谢
She's that lady I was telling you about.
她就是那位我跟你提到过的女士
She's gonna be a big part of your life.
她会成为你生活中的一部分
I'm scared. What if she's not nice?
我害怕,万一她不好怎么办?
Look.
看
See these right here? These are magic sunglasses, okay?
看到吗?这是神奇太阳镜,明白吗?
If you're afraid, put them on to become invisible.
如果害怕,戴上你就可以隐形了
Really? Nobody can see me?
真的?谁也看不见我?
Put them on.
戴上
Sonny, I'm right here.
Sonny,我在这儿
Oh, the glasses. I couldn't see you.
哦,太阳镜,我看不见你
Keep those on. No one can notice you until you decide they can.
戴着吧 只要你不想,谁也看不见你
-Okay. -Let's go.
- 好 - 走吧
I'm still right here.
我还在这儿
Okay, all right, the glasses.
哦,对,你戴着太阳镜呢
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
Who's that?
那是谁?
Who's who? He's invisible.
谁是谁?他是隐身的
Can I come in?
我能进来吗?
Sure.
当然
Any invisible people out here...
有隐身人在这儿的话
...feel free to come in, okay?
就进来吧,好吗?
Sonny, I don't really know what's going on right now.
Sonny,我不太清楚发生了什么
-We should talk-- -You said I got some thinking to do?
- 但我们该谈谈… - 你上次说我该考虑考虑
So I did it.
我考虑了
Just because I don't have a job doesn't mean I don't wanna move on.
我没有工作不代表我不上进
Instead of saying that, I figured I'd show you.
我认为光这样说,不如做给你看
-Before you say anything-- -Look at that.
- 在你说什么之前,我只想让你知道… - 看哪
He took his sunglasses off.
他摘掉太阳镜了
He wants you to see him. He likes you.
他希望你看见他,他喜欢你
Julian, come here.
Julian,过来
Come here, pal.
过来,小家伙
Vanessa...
Vanessa
...l want you to meet Julian, my son.
我想让你见见 Julian,我儿子
Our son. I adopted him.
我们的儿子,我收养了他
I don't know what to say.
我不知道该说什么
Don't say anything.
什么也不要说了
Is someone in the bathroom?
卫生间有人吗?
Why is the door shut?
门为什么关着?
I don't know.
我不知道
You don't?
你不知道?
I can't believe this.
我无法相信
Open up.
开门
Open the door!
把门打开!
-Is everything okay? -Oh, my God.
- 一切都正常吧? - 噢,我的天
I'm sorry. I was freaking out there.
对不起,我太失礼了
-I'm Sonny. -Sid.
- 我是 Sonny - Sid
I had an attack of paranoia. I thought you were sleeping with my girl.
我精神错乱了 我以为你和我女朋友上床了
I am.
没错
What's that?
你说什么?
That's what I was trying to tell you before. I found someone.
刚才我想告诉你的,我找到别人了
-This old guy? -Sid.
- 这个老家伙? - Sid
He's already achieved so much...
他已经取得了很多成就
...and yet he's still goal-oriented and still focused.
但现在仍然为自己的目标奋斗
And he has a five-year plan.
而且他有个5年计划
What is it? " Don't die"?
什么计划?"不翘辫子"?
I can't believe this. We got a family now. This is what you wanted.
我不能相信我们现在有个家庭了 我以为这是你想要的
You surprising me with a kid that you adopted...
你带着你收养的孩子来让我惊奇
-...wasn't what I wanted. -I did this for you.
- 并不是我想要的 - 我这样做是为了你
You wanted me to be more responsible. I can't raise this kid alone.
你希望我更有责任感 我一个人无法抚养这个孩子
You remind me of my grandson. You don't think things through.
你让我想起了我孙子 你考虑问题很简单
Hey, Old Man River, zip it or I'll break your hip.
嘿,老头儿,闭嘴 否则我打烂你屁股
-I'd like to see you try it. -Shut up.
- 我倒想见识一下 - 闭嘴
How'd you misconstrue the situation so badly?
你怎么完全误解了我的意思?
I don't know.
我不知道
Deep down you must've known this day was coming.
其实你早知道会有这一天
You made the biggest mistake of your life.
你犯了你一生最大的错误
I know you'll be missing me when you got...
我知道,你肯定会想我,当
...that big, white, wrinkly...
一个又大又白又皱的
...body on top of you...
身体压在你身上
...with his loose skin...
还有松松的皮
...and old balls.
和两个老蛋蛋
Gross.
恶心
Excuse me. How you doing? I'm Kevin Gerrity.
不好意思,你好 我是 Kevin Gerrity
I got an emergency problem. Is Arthur Brooks around?
我有急事,Arthur Brooks 在吗?
I'll go get him for you.
我去叫他
Stay where I can see you. I gotta talk to this guy.
待在我能看见你的地方 我要跟这家伙谈谈
Mr. Gerrity?
Gerrity 先生?
-Arthur Brooks. -How are you? I need to speak with you.
- 我是 Arthur Brooks - 你好吗?我要和你谈谈
I didn't tell you to come here, did l?
我没说需要你来这儿吧?
I was gonna mail you the paperwork.
因为我正打算把相关文件寄给你
It's like the opposite of that.
正相反
Look, I can't manage this kid.
我无法抚养这孩子了
I ain't a good father. I made a big mistake.
我不是个好父亲,我犯了个大错误
Mistake?
错误?
I had a mother lined up for him...
我本来要再给她找个母亲
...but she's banging the Pepperidge Farm guy.
但她跟别人搞上了
The kid won't stop peeing and throwing up.
这孩子总是撒尿扔东西
He's like a cocker spaniel. I just....
他就像只小可卡犬,我都…
He'd be better off with his natural mother.
我认为他跟着亲生母亲会好些
Well, she passed away last night, Mr. Gerrity.
哦,她昨晚刚过世,Gerrity 先生
She had cancer. She must have sensed that her time was running short.
她得了癌症,她肯定已经感觉到 自己的时间不多了
She wanted her son to be with the natural father.
所以想把孩子交给亲生父亲 很有道理
Loop.
绕
Pull.
拉
If you don't wanna take care of him...
如果你不想抚养他
...we'll take him. But he'll have to chill in a group home.
我们会的,但我得告诉你 他就得呆在一个大家庭里
Group home? Like an orphanage?
大家庭?比如孤儿院?
We don't call them that.
是,但现在不这么叫
Look, I did it. Loop, swoop and pull.
看,我会了,绕,穿,拉
You did do it.
你确实会了
Congratulations, kid.
祝贺你,孩子
I showed him that.
我教他的
Why don't you go back over there, okay?
你先去待在那边,好吗?
-I'll call the Heatherton Home-- -Let's do this.
- 我来给 Heatherton 之家打电话… - 要不我们这样
I'll hang onto the kid until you find him a new family.
在你给他找到新家庭之前 孩子还是我来照顾
I don't know. I gotta watch out for the kid's best interest.
我不能决定得看孩子自己想要怎么样
You said yourself you were a bogus dad.
你刚才说自己是个不称职的爸爸
He's better off with me than in an orphanage.
他跟着我总比进孤儿院强
I don't wanna put him in a home any more than you do.
我也一样想给他找个家
Why don't we pretend you didn't even come in here?
不如我们假装你今天根本没来过?
I'll give you a shout when I line up a family.
等我找到收养家庭会通知你
-That's good. -Later.
- 太好了 - 再见
Just don't make me regret this.
就是别让我失望
Where are we going now?
我们现在去哪儿?
I gotta make a phone call. Just stay right here, all right?
我要打个电话,待在这儿,好吗?
-This is a collect call from: -Your baby boy
- 这是接收方付费电话,来自… - 你的宝贝儿子
-To accept charges, say, "Yes " -Yeah, I'll accept.
- 确认付费,请答复,"是" - 好,我确认
Dad, how's it going? How's Florida?
爸,怎么样?佛罗里达好玩吗?
Not too bad. Your mother got a sunburn playing tennis.
还不赖,你妈妈昨天打网球晒伤了
-I got some interesting news. -Oh, yeah? What?
- 我有些有趣的消息 - 哦,是吗?什么?
Kind of adopted a kid.
类似收养个小孩
What do you mean?
什么意思?
I'm talking about you being a grandfather.
我的意思是你当爷爷了恭喜了
Who the hell would give you a kid?
谁他妈的会把小孩给你?
Social Services.
社会服务处
You idiot. You better give that kid back.
你个白痴,最好送回去
His mother's....
他的妈妈
Hang on.
等等
Go play with them pigeons, buddy.
去和鸽子玩吧
I tried to give him back. I just can't. All right?
我想送回去的,但不行,明白吗?
I need your help.
我需要你的帮助
I'm in a bad way Vanessa dumped me I don't know what I'm doing
我现在情况很糟,Vanessa 把我甩了 我不知道我在干嘛
You're damn right.
该死的你说的没错
The kid is always around.
孩子总是缠着我
He never leaves me alone.
过去3天他从不让我清闲
You'd think he'd want some privacy. I'm in deep shit.
我以为他有自己的空间 我陷入麻烦了
Give that kid back before you ruin both your lives.
在你毁掉你俩的生活之前 把孩子送回去
I appreciate that.
谢谢你的建议,爸爸
He's better off living in a dumpster.
他住在垃圾堆里也比跟你住强
I'll be a better father than you!
我会做个比你更好的父亲的!
Impossible! All you care about is yourself!
不可能!你只在乎你自己!
Yeah? No, I care about you saving money on this call!
是吗?不,我很在乎你 我不浪费你的电话费了!
Let's eat.
我们去吃东西
The Vanessa thing did not work out.
搞不定 Vanessa 了
She lost her damn mind. That wasn't your fault, though, okay?
她精神失常了 并不是你的错,明白吗?
I know when you first got here, you thought you were gonna meet your dad.
我知道你刚过来的时候 以为能见到你爸爸
But I don't think that's gonna happen.
但我认为现在不可能了
Why?
为什么?
I don't know.
不知道
But, buddy, real dads aren't always that great.
但是,兄弟,亲生爸爸并不一定很伟大
I got one and he's out of his mind.
我有一个,但他疯了
He tells me what to do. He never lets me figure stuff out on my own.
他让我做这做那 却从来不让我为自己的生活做决定
A lot of dads are like that. That's why people grow up nuts.
很多爸爸都是这样的 这就是为什么很多人长大后就废了
Look at this guy.
瞧这个家伙
He was probably a nice boy like you. Then his dad messed his mind up.
他可能以前也像你这么乖 然后他老爸把他给毁了
Who won the Jets game?
Jets 队那场比赛谁赢了?
Who cares?
管他呢
Let it go. He can't control you anymore.
算了吧,他以后控制不了你了
What do you mean?
你什么意思?
You know.
你明白的
You're a loser.
对,你是个没用的家伙
You're mad at your dad, not at me! I forgive you!
你在生你爸的气,不是我! 我原谅你!
I am. I am. I hate my father.
对,是的,我恨我爸
I don't want it to be like that. I don't wanna control you.
看见吗,我可不想那样 我不想控制你
You even like your name?
你喜欢 Julian 这个名字吗?
I guess.
大概喜欢
You guess? Shouldn't you like your name?
大概?你的名字自己得喜欢啊
It'll be your name the rest of your life.
为什么不自己挑个名字 名字要陪伴你一辈子呢
What do you want?
你想叫什么?
Frankenstein.
弗兰肯斯坦(科学怪人)
I can deal with that. I'll call you Frankenstein.
我能接受,以后我就叫你弗兰肯斯坦
Frankenstein, you gonna play in the puddle?
干嘛?弗兰肯斯坦,你要玩脏水?
Go ahead. From now on, you do whatever you wanna do.
玩吧,从现在起,想干什么就干什么
I'll show you some cool shit along the way.
一会我教你些好玩的
That's what it's all about.
这个样子才对嘛
Stay in front of it. Don't be scared.
接球,别怕
It's coming right at you.
朝你打过来了
Okay. All right.
很好,不错
You're picking your head up. Don't do that.
你得抬起头来,别那样
Is this okay?
这样行吗?
That's what you wanna wear?
你想穿成这样?
That's okay with me then.
那我就不反对
Good luck walking down the street.
祝你在街上好运,我只能这么说了
Way to block it. Stay with it.
还不行想办法接住
You're the next Willie Randolph.
你就是下一个 Willie Randolph (洋基队球星),记住
Chief Jay Strongbow used to do a sleeper hold.
摔角明星常用这一招
Put your arm under here.
把胳膊放在这儿
Lift this arm, okay? Slide under and try to lock wrists.
抬起这只胳膊,行吗?手腕用力扣住
Let me show you. Watch.
扣住我示范一下看好
Throw him into the ropes and he comes back....
把他扔向场边,他又弹回来
Get him. Get him. Lock him up.
抓住他抓住他扣住他
Lock wrists.
手腕扣紧
You bring him down slow.
慢慢把他放倒
Apply pressure.
施加压力
He's going to sleep now.
他要昏过去了
See, he's out.
瞧,他被击倒了
Wake up.
醒来
You'll be the only kid your age with a slingshot.
你将是同龄人里唯一有弹弓的,我保证
Go have some fun. Shoot a few beer cans or something.
去好好玩吧,打打易拉罐什么的
You like that?
你喜欢?
Sonny, Sonny, come here!
Sonny,Sonny,快过来!
What is it? What's the matter?
什么?怎么了?
Let me have that.
还是给我吧
Go to your room. I think. Or do whatever you want.
去你的房间,或者随便你干什么
It's gonna be fun. You nervous?
肯定会很有趣,你紧张吗?
No? You're excited, aren't you?
不?你很兴奋吧?
Let's go. Up, up, up.
开始上,上,上
Here comes some candy.
有糖吃了
How you doing?
你好吗?
Happy Halloween! We got a first-timer.
万圣节快乐!我们是第一个
Do the right thing, buddy.
做你该做的,伙计
We want some candy!
我们要糖!
Hang on right here for a second. Don't move.
在这儿等一会儿,不要走开
Yeah, that's it.
对了,这还差不多
Yeah, CDs. You like that?
好的,CD你喜欢吗?
He's not happy. What else you got?
他不开心,你还有什么?
Okay, that's good. Trick-or-treat.
好了,不错不给就捣乱
Say, " Happy Halloween."
说"万圣节快乐"
Thank you.
谢谢
Next year, be prepared, moron.
明年要早点准备好,傻瓜
What's with the cummerbund?
孩子穿的那是什么
I let him wear whatever he wants.
我让他穿自己想穿的
Those boots are the best.
那靴子最棒了
I think they're Kevin's.
我想那是 Kevin 的
I'll have a hot dog with the mustard and a knish.
我要个加芥末和奶酪的热狗
Frankenstein, what do you want?
弗兰肯斯坦,你要什么?
Thirty packets of ketchup.
三十包番茄酱
All right. Thirty packets of ketchup.
好的,三十包番茄酱
Nice cut, pal.
打得好,伙计
Frankenstein.
弗兰肯斯坦
Do that thing I taught you the other day.
做一下那天我教你的
It took him 20 minutes to learn that. He's quick. He's smart.
他用了20分钟就学会了 很快,很聪明
-And he loves ketchup. -He does.
- 而且他喜欢番茄酱 - 是啊
This is a whole new school of child-raising.
这是种全新的教育方式
You give him options, not orders. Let him make the decision.
你给他选择,而不是命令 让他自己决定
You're a pioneer.
你真是个先锋
-So you two just chill out all day? -Basically.
- 那你们俩成天都在一起? - 基本上
Hung out on the monkey bars. The kid did eight chin-ups.
昨天我们去公园 这小子在单杠上连做了8个引体向上
I can't even do one with these scrawny arms.
8个,我这细胳膊连一个都做不了
They're not scrawny. They're nice.
不细,很好呢
What do you wanna do tomorrow?
Julian,你明天干什么?
I wanna go to school.
我想去上学
I don't force him, he makes the right decision. Way to go.
瞧,我没强迫他,他做了正确的决定 很不错
We'll enroll you on Monday. Enjoy the weekend.
我们周一去报名好吧 再好好过个周末
Do the thing again.
再做一次
That one touched the ground.
这次碰到地面了
That was awesome!
太厉害了!
Good job.
干得漂亮
Help me! Help me!
帮帮我!帮帮我!
Please help me. I don't know where I live.
请帮帮我,我不知道我家在哪里
This isn't a big problem.
这不是什么大问题
We'll find your parents.
我会找到你的父母的
-What's your name? -Frankenstein.
- 你叫什么? - 弗兰肯斯坦
There you are.
你在这儿
There you are. Are you okay, buddy?
你在这儿,你没事吧?
I turn my head and he disappeared.
我一转头他就不见了
Don't you ever do that to me again. Don't do that.
以后不要再这样了,别再这样
Thank you for being sweet to my little boy.
谢谢你对我的小宝贝这么好
You're welcome, Sonny.
别客气,Sonny
I think my sister, Corinne, is engaged to your roommate.
我想我妹妹 Corinne已经 和你室友订婚了
Your sister's Corinne? That sucks.
你妹妹是 Corinne ?真是的
Yeah, I'm up from D.C. I was at that party...
是啊,我从华盛顿特区来 那天我也在,我们…
...where we wasted the good surprise on you.
把惊喜浪费在你身上的那个晚会
Sorry about that.
那事我很抱歉
So, what, you have a son now?
怎么,你现在有儿子了?
I'm not his dad. I'm more of a father-figure type...
我不是他爸,我只是临时充当父亲
...until Social Services can get another family.
直到社会服务处 找到另外一个家庭领养他
At which point, you'll find a new way...
这样,你也有了个
...to initiate conversations with girls in the park.
在公园里和女孩搭讪的好方法
Yeah, that's correct.
对,没错
Good job, buddy!
干得好,伙计!
He's peeing on his own.
他在自己撒尿
Keep it flowing! That's it!
继续!对了!
Go! Go!
加油! 加油!
So does Corinne's sister have a name?
那么 Corinne 的姐姐有名字吗?
It's Layla.
我叫 Layla
Layla? I like your song.
Layla ?我喜欢你的歌
Could you do me a favour?
能帮我个忙吗?
Could you hang out with me?
能和我约会吗?
He'll think he's a failure if he couldn't get me a date.
如果你不跟我约会,他会认为他很失败 我不想让孩子失望
I really can't.
真的不行
I have a ton of work to do.
我有好多事要做
I see. Hang on a second.
这样啊,等一下
Come here.
过来
Layla, if you don't come over to Sonny's apartment tonight...
Layla,如果你今晚不来 Sonny 的公寓
...there's a good chance I'll develop a stutter.
我很可能会变成结巴
P-P-P-Please don't do this to me.
请 请 请不要这样对我
-That is so cheap. -What?
- 这招太阴了 - 不行吗?
So I'm working in a tollbooth now.
于是我现在在收费站工作
I originally wanted to be a male model...
我本想当一名男模
...but I'm not very good-looking, so that didn't work out.
但我不够帅,所以没成功
I'm sorry to hear that.
听到这个我很难过
I'm all right. I'm recovering.
我没事,我在恢复
This is my favourite part of the song right here.
这首歌我最喜欢这一段
If I can't have you
如果不能拥有你
Better keep it down low. The kid's gonna wake up.
还是小声点,孩子会被吵醒的
Too late.
晚了
Okay. Just hang out a little bit.
好吧,就去一会
I'll be right back. Don't go sneaking out.
我很快回来,别溜走了
-What are you doing? -You forgot to say good night.
- 你干嘛? - 你忘了说晚安
What do you mean?
什么意思
I can't go to sleep until you say good night.
你不说晚安我就睡不着
I didn't know that. I'm sorry. Good night.
我并不知道,对不起,晚安
Go to sleep now, all right?
现在睡吧,好吗?
What'd we learn about girls?
今天对泡妞有什么心得?
Initiating the conversation is half the battle.
搭讪是成功的一半
Bingo. Now sleep, okay?
答对了,现在睡觉,好吧?
I gave him NyQuil. He should be out for the night.
哄他睡着了,他整晚都不会醒了
This is Styx. They've been my favourite band since I was 1 2.
这是 Styx 乐队,我从12岁开始就很喜欢
You're kidding me.
你开玩笑
No, I can't help it. I just love them.
没有,我就是很喜欢他们
My friends make fun of me.
朋友们都笑我
My friends make fun of me too. I've seen them 25 times.
我的朋友们也笑我 我见了他们25次
Tommy Shaw, when I was 1 6, I was at the concert...
Tommy Shaw,16岁时 在他的演唱会上
...and he reached down, pulled me on stage.
他伸手把我拉上舞台
I did the robot voice for " Mr. Roboto."
我模仿了"机器人先生"的声音
Really?
真的
No, I made that up. I'm sorry.
不,我瞎编的,对不起
That would've been cool, right?
要是真那样就酷了,对吧?
My cousin's friends with their drummer...
但我表弟的朋友认识他们的鼓手
...so when they come to town, we go to dinner...
所以他们来镇上的时候 我们就一起吃饭
...and they tell us stories from the road.
他们就把路上发生的故事告诉我们
Really?
真的?
No, I made that up again too. I'm sorry.
假的,我又瞎编的,对不起
You're not attracted to, like, 60-year-old guys, are you?
你对像60岁老头没兴趣吧?
Yeah, I don't like them either.
对,我也不喜欢他们
I can't sleep.
我睡不着
He can't sleep.
他睡不着
So the rabbit ran across the street...
于是兔子跑过街
...because he thought he saw some carrots.
因为他以为看到了胡萝卜
But when he got across the street...
但当他到街对面的时候
...it turned out they weren't carrots, they were peanuts.
发现不是胡萝卜,是花生
Peanuts?
花生?
The peanuts belonged to a squirrel...
花生是一只松鼠
...who had taken them home from a baseball game.
带回家的
And then the rabbit thought to himself...
然后兔子想
..." Carrots, peanuts, what's the difference?"
"胡萝卜,花生,也没什么区别吧?"
So he asked the squirrel if he could have some.
于是他请求松鼠给他一点
And the squirrel said, "Of course."
松鼠说,"当然可以"
And the rabbit was very happy to make such a nice new friend.
兔子非常高兴能交到一个这么好的新朋友
And so was the squirrel.
松鼠也是这么觉得
And the rabbit thought the squirrel had pretty hair.
兔子觉得松鼠的头发很美
And nice eyes also.
还有美丽的双眼
And the squirrel thought the rabbit was really nice too.
松鼠也觉得兔子真的很好
And then, the rabbit worked up his courage...
然后,兔子鼓起勇气
...and asked the squirrel if he could have...
请求松鼠,他可不可以
...just the littlest squirrel kiss.
吻兔子一下
And the squirrel thought it just wasn't the right time...
松鼠认为还不是
...in her busy squirrel life to be kissing any rabbits...
该吻兔子的时候
...even though this particular rabbit was very sweet.
尽管这只特别的兔子很不错
And the rabbit got shut down, did he?
兔子就被拒绝了,对吧?
That's all right. But he was still thinking maybe...
没关系,但他还在想,也许
...Scuba Steve could get a squirrel kiss...
Scuba Steve 可以得到松鼠一吻
...so somebody's getting some action.
总得有人做点什么吧
Good night, Scuba Steve.
晚安,Scuba Steve
Good night, Frankenstein.
晚安,弗兰肯斯坦
Good night, Sonny.
晚安,Sonny
Good night, Layla.
晚安,Layla
Don't get caught with any girls.
别一下被某个女孩迷住
It's your first day. Take it slow.
这只是第一天,有得是时间
I'll meet you after school at 2:30, right out front.
2:30放学时我来接你,就在大门口
You're not staying?
你不留下?
No, I gotta go get you some more ketchup.
不行,我得去再给你弄些番茄酱
I don't like these kids.
我不喜欢这些小孩
I don't either, but shouldn't we give them a chance?
我也不太喜欢 但我们给他们个机会吧?
How's this?
这样如何?
Here are the magic sunglasses.
给你神奇太阳镜
You put them on if you feel scared, okay?
害怕的话就戴上,好吧?
I lost you.
我找不到你了
I don't know where you are. I'm sorry.
我不知道你在哪儿,对不起
Oh, there you go.
噢,原来在这儿
You go inside and make some friends.
进去交些朋友吧
Oh, yeah, that's a good hug.
噢,好,这个拥抱不错
All right. Go inside. I'm gonna miss you.
好了,进去吧,我会想你的
Hi, I like your hat.
Hi,我喜欢你的帽子
What's your name?
你叫什么?
-Might as well-- -Leave a message!
- 也可以… - 留个口信!
Mr Gerrity, this is Arthur Brooks from Social Services I got good news
Gerrity 先生,我是社会服务处的 Arthur Brooks,有个好消息
We may have found a family for Julian
我们给 Julian 找到了一个领养家庭
Give me a call back as soon as possible
请尽快给我回个电话
so we can set up a meeting Bye
以便我们安排见面,再见
Sierra Club Legal Department.
山峦保护协会法务部
Can I speak to Layla Maloney?
我找 Layla Maloney
Layla, line four.
Layla,4号线
You're a lawyer?
你是律师吗?
What are you doing?
你干嘛?
Waiting for Julian so I can have somebody to play with.
等 Julian 放学,所以想找个人一起玩
-What are you doing? -I'm swamped.
- 你在干嘛? - 我忙死了
I gotta do my laundry on my lunch hour.
我还得在午餐时间把衣服都洗了
I was gonna do my laundry today too. Where are you going?
我今天也打算洗衣服的 你去哪儿洗?
There's a place nearby, Suds, on Bleecker.
附近有个洗衣房 叫 Suds,在 Bleecker 街
I know that place. Maybe I'll see you there then.
那地方我认识,那到时在那见吧
Maybe. I gotta go.
或许吧,我得走了
I bought tickets, and the show was the night before
于是我买到了票 但表演是前天晚上的
Maybe it was a mistake
也许是弄错了
That's nice, but you don't know what's going down on the streets.
真不错,我还以为你对流行的东西不了解呢
It's hard to know what's going down...
是很难了解到
...when you're in an office seven days a week, Mr. Tollbooth.
特别是像我这样一周7天都呆在办公室 收费站先生
You're not gonna tell me to get a real job.
你不是想让我找个真正的工作吧
No. You're a big boy.
不,你是个大男孩
It's cool you only work one day a week.
你一周只工作一天,真爽
These are the cutest things I've ever seen.
噢,这是我见过最可爱的东西
I know.
对,我知道
I have them in yellow. I wear them when I work out.
我自己只有黄色的,脏了也看不出来
It's great what you're doing with Julian while you got him.
你有了 Julian 后你做得很不错
Yeah, well, I got him.
是,对,我现在有了他
I read an article that said...
我读了一篇文章,上面说
...the most important influences in a kid's life are his friends.
对孩子一生影响最大的是他的朋友
They said that?
真有这种说法?
Just hope he's not hanging out with drug dealers and delinquents in school.
但愿他在学校不要和毒贩和小混混一起玩
I'm kidding.
开个玩笑
I know. I know.
我知道,我知道
Man, this Yoo-hoo is good. You know what else is good?
Yoo hoo 饮料真棒 你知道还有什么能让人感觉这么棒?
Smoking dope.
吸毒
I ain't going to rat you out.
我不会告发你的
Puffing the cheeba.
吸大麻
Go by the seesaw, smoke a J. You know what I'm talking about?
吃摇头丸,迷幻药 你懂我在说什么吗?
I have a bellybutton.
我有肚脐眼
You have a bellybutton? We all have bellybuttons.
你有肚脐眼?我们都有啊
And we all love Yoo-hoo. Especially with a little rum.
而且我们都喜欢 Yoo hoo 特别是加了朗姆酒的Yoo hoo
What's rum?
什么是朗姆酒?
You don't know?
你不知道?
Rumpelstiltskin?
是朗姆怪?
Rumpelstiltskin's a good man. So are you guys.
朗姆怪是好人,你们也是
Stay clean. Stay focused.
要洁身自好,保持坚定,保持坚强
Frankenstein, have fun with your friends.
好了,弗兰肯斯坦 你可以和朋友们玩了
Why are you scratching so much?
为什么一直抓?
I have ecza....
我有疹子
Eczema? Gross.
疹子?真恶心
How do I make it stop itching?
怎样才能不痒啊?
I don't know. You scratch it.
不知道,你多抓一抓
SpaghettiO's. Do you like SpaghettiO's?
SpaghettiO's 喜欢吃 SpaghettiO's吗?
Dented cans are half price.
罐子扁了就只要半价
Microsoft went down three points. We gotta save some money.
我们的微软股票跌了3点 我们要省点儿钱了
Here, give it a shot.
来,摔一下
That's it, boy.
对了,孩子
Put it in there. Feels good.
放进来吧,感觉真好
Hi, Sonny. Hi, Sonny's friend.
Hi,Sonny,Hi,Sonny 的朋友
His name's Frankenstein.
他叫弗兰肯斯坦
Hi, Frankenstein. Remember me?
Hi,弗兰肯斯坦,记得我吗?
Help me. I'm lost. I don't know where I am.
帮帮我,我迷路了 我不知道自己在哪儿
You don't gotta do that.
不用再这样了
You guys wear the same size T-shirt. That's cool.
看呐,你们穿的T恤一样大,真酷
I heard you did laundry with my sister.
我听说你和我姐姐 一起去洗衣房洗衣服?
She said we did laundry?
她说我们是一起洗衣服?
Where I'm from, it's called doing the hibbity-dibbity.
因为据我所知 我们是一起那样那样
I got eczema.
我有疹子
Well, then you shouldn't scratch it.
那你就不能抓
Don't tell him what to do. He can scratch.
不要教他该做什么 他想抓就让他抓
-Scratch. -Is that better?
- 抓吧 - 这样好点吗?
-Thank you. -You're welcome.
- 谢谢 - 不客气
You know about kids? I thought you were a foot doctor.
我不知道你还了解孩子 我还以为你是个赤脚医生
It's not doctor stuff. It's common sense. Scratching spreads rashes.
这和医生没关系,你真蠢 这是常识,抓会让疹子扩散
This is something you learned at Hooters.
这也是你当舞女时学的吧
-What the hell is he doing? -He's shopping.
- 他到底在干嘛? - 他在购物
Microsoft went down three points.
我们的微软股票跌了3点
That's good. See you later, Frankenstein.
真不错,再见,弗兰肯斯坦
Stay away from the frozen-food section. Your boobs'll harden.
离冷冻区远点,你的胸会冻硬的
Isn't Little ltaly the greatest?
小意大利很不错吧?
I like it. Everyone always tells me to hang out in the Village and SoHo.
我喜欢这儿 以前我都只去格林威治村和 SoHo 区玩
That's all right.
那也挺好
But you gotta respect a place where the fatter you are, the cooler you are.
但是你也得尊重一个越胖越受欢迎的地方
Last time, he was with a different girl. I guess he ate her.
上次,他是和另外一个女孩在一起 他一定是把她给吃了
I went to Coney lsland today with the little boy.
我今天和小家伙去了 Coney 岛
You gotta take a look at this.
你得看看这个
We had a blast together.
我们一起拍了快照
He's so happy.
他好开心
He is such a good boy.
他是个好孩子
If I have a kid of my own, I hope he's half as cool as that kid.
如果我自己有孩子 要能有这孩子一半好就行了
Is he picking your nose?
他在挖你的鼻子?
Yeah, he was picking his own all day...
对,他整天挖自己的
-...so I figured he could borrow mine. -Sweet.
- 所以我想他可以借用我的 - 真好玩
He must be miserable without you right now.
他现在没有你陪一定很难过
No, he's in good hands.
不,有人在照顾他
Look at Brad's body. Not an ounce of fat on it.
瞧 Brad 的身材,一点脂肪都没有
-What? -Don't worry. I like yours better.
- 什么? - 别担心,我更喜欢你的身材
I got two queens, two jacks and an ace.
我有两张Q,两张J 还有一张A
-I win. -Why do you win?
- 我赢了 - 为什么你赢?
I got a two, a four, a ten, an eight and a six.
我有一张2,一张4,一张10 一张8和一张6
I don't understand. Why do you win?
我不明白,那为什么你赢?
-Because I win. -What's the name of that game?
- 因为我赢了 - 你们在玩什么?
I win.
我赢
I'll get it!
我来开
-What's up? -I'm looking for Kevin Gerrity.
- 什么事? - 我找 Kevin Gerrity
He's in China. Who are you?
他在中国,你是谁?
Arthur Brooks, New York City Social Services. I'm confused.
Arthur Brooks,纽约市社会服务处的 我糊涂了
Chinatown. He loves those egg rolls.
他在唐人街,他喜欢吃蛋卷
I've tried contacting him several times and he hasn't responded.
哦,我联系了他好几次,他都没有回应
I'm concerned.
我想知道怎么回事
Ixnay on the ketchupnay.
嘿,不要吃番茄酱了
-Have him call me. -All right.
- 让他打电话给我 - 好的
My body's definitely better than his.
我的体型绝对比他好
Without question.
毫无疑问
It took you a long time to pencil me in. You work all the time.
我好长时间才排进你的日程 你总是在工作
I know. I'm excited.
我知道,我很兴奋
You're excited. How long you been this crazy?
你是很兴奋 你这么疯狂工作有多久了?
I guess ever since I was a little girl.
我想,当我还是小女孩的时候
See, my mom got married really young and pretty much just raised us kids.
是这样,我妈很年轻时就结婚 然后生了我们
So when my dad took off...
所以当我爸走掉时
...she wasn't left with a lot of options.
她这辈子就算这样了
And I think that's when I decided...
我想我就是那时决定
...that I never wanted to end up in that situation.
我永远不能重蹈妈妈的覆辙
That's actually a good reason to be working.
这确实是不停工作的好理由
I guess I feel like I gotta kick ass while there's ass to be kicked.
我可能觉得,有事情要做我就要不停去做
You kick that ass during the day, but at night you have fun with Sonny.
白天你做你那些事 但晚上就和 Sonny 开心地玩吧
The Best of Times
The Best of Times
Are when I'm alone with you
Are when I'm alone with you
Some rain, some shine
Some rain,some shine
Two guys you were best friends with in law school fell in love with each other?
那么你在法律学校最好的两个哥们儿 彼此相爱了?
Is that strange for you?
你是不是觉得很怪异?
No. Nothing changed, really.
不,没什么改变,其实
They watch a different kind of porno now. But that's it.
虽然现在他们看另一类型的A片了 但也就这点变化
My God! This is Corinne's place?
老天!这就是 Corinne 的家?
If the girls at Hooters could see her now.
如果她的舞女朋友看见了一定会这样说
-Do you want your ass kicked? -I'm just kidding around, Layla.
- 你想挨踢啊? - 我在开玩笑呢,Layla
You're afraid to get involved and you got a lot of work, but...
我知道你害怕恋爱而且 工作也很忙,但…
...when I'm not with you, I'm thinking of you. Do you have that going on?
当我不和你在一起的时候,总是想你 你会这样吗?
Maybe.
可能吧
Maybe we should try a kiss out.
或许我们该试试吻一下
We owe it to ourselves to see if we should move to the next level.
这能帮我们确定 我们是否该发展到下一个阶段
I'm not sure.
我不确定
Me either. It's just that you kissed Scuba Steve.
我也一样,只是你吻过了 Scuba Steve
Ever since then, he's strutted around bragging...
从那以后,他总是在我面前炫耀
..." I got a kiss the first night. After three times, you got nothing."
"我第一晚就得到一个吻 你都第三次约会了还什么也没有"
-He said that? -Come on.
- 他那样说? - 来吧
Let's just give it a shot just so I can have some dignity.
我们来试一下,也好让我有点尊严
All right?
好吗?
Oh, my God!
哦,我的天!
Gross!
真恶心!
Did I witness the first kiss?
我见证了你们的初吻?
Yeah, you did. Thanks a lot for showing up.
对,没错,多谢你的出现
Layla, you didn't actually enjoy that, did you?
Layla,你一定觉得不怎么样吧?
I don't know. I'm going upstairs.
不知道,我上楼了
Wash your mouth out. He's dirty.
把嘴巴洗干净,他很脏
And he's poor.
而且没钱
What do you got in the bag, Corinne? Some chicken wings? Booby tassels?
嘿,你袋子里有什么,Corinne ? 鸡翅?胸罩?
Shut up.
闭嘴
You have a good sleep.
睡个好觉
Pleasant Hooters.
令人愉快的舞女
Come on, come on!
快来,快来!
This is where we hang our jackets.
这是我们挂外套的地方
This is my hook.
这个钩子是我的
That's a capertillar.
那是只虫毛
A caterpillar.
一个,毛虫吧
-That's right, a capertillar. -Capertillar, all right.
- 对,虫毛 - 虫毛,好吧
-Staying clean, pal? -Yes.
- 你有洁身自好吧? - 有的
You drink the booze, you lose. Remember that, punk.
你要是喝酒,你就输了,记住,小子
I'm Julian's teacher, Ms. Foote.
我是 Julian 的老师,Foote 女士
-You his father? -I'm Kevin Gerrity.
- 你是他父亲? - 我是 Kevin Gerrity
Do you have some time to go over some things that have been bothering me?
有些事情让我很困扰 你有时间解释一下吗?
Sure.
当然
Go take a walk, pal.
去玩会儿,孩子
Julian has been displaying some odd behaviour.
Julian 有些古怪的举动
He spilled glue on the floor and didn't tell anyone.
上周他把胶水洒在地板上却不告诉别人
He covered it with newspaper.
他只是用报纸盖起来
And then one of our students wore Rollerblades for show-and-tell.
还有,一个学生穿着轮滑给我们表演
And Julian tripped him with a stick.
Julian 却扔了根木棍把他绊到了
I've never--
我从没有…
Julian found it hilarious.
Julian 觉得这样很好玩
I like him to express himself freely.
我喜欢他自由的表达自己
I've really never seen any problems with that.
真的从来没见过他干这种事
Your boy's making the least progress of any of the children.
在所有孩子中,你的孩子进步最慢
Frankly, his personal hygiene is becoming a cause for concern.
坦白的讲,他的个人卫生也很让人关心
He's the smelly kid in class? I let him become the smelly kid?
他是班里最臭的孩子? 我会让他变成全班最臭的孩子?
What's wrong with me?
我有病啊?
I've had some smelly ones before.
我以前也见过身上有味道的孩子
But your son is by far the smelliest.
但你儿子是目前为止最臭的
All right, I got you. What do you think I should do?
好了,我知道了,放松 你要我怎么做呢?
Start by paying more attention to his schoolwork.
在他身上多花点时间
The class is giving a presentation of the Founding Fathers.
班里在准备"开国元勋"的表演
Julian has drawn the part of Benjamin Franklin, a very important role.
Julian 扮演一个很重要的角色 本杰明·富兰克林
Do what you can to help.
尽量帮帮忙
I will turn this all around. That's a promise.
我会让他改正的,我保证
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
Stinky, let's go. You got us in trouble.
臭东西,我们走,你惹麻烦了
Did he call him "Stinky"?
他叫他"臭东西"?
Wow, I didn't know this about George Washington.
哇,我不知道乔治华盛顿的这事
Yes, his teeth were made of wool.
对,他的牙齿是布头做的
Wood.
木头
I sorry. I mix up " D" and " L."
对不起,我把"布"和"木"搞混了
Well, get it right.
嗯,改过来吧
Turn that game off, pal.
把游戏机关了,伙计
I got four guys left.
再干掉4个就过关了
Let's study a little bit.
我们来学习
I don't wanna study.
我不想学习
Give me that.
给我
-You just killed me. -So what? You'll play later.
- 你把我弄死了 - 那又怎么样?一会再玩
You can't tell me what to do.
你不该告诉我该做什么
Really? Let's take a vote. Who thinks the kid should study?
真的?我们来投票 认为这小孩该学习的举手
Who doesn't? Well, you just lost, two to one.
认为不该的?好,你输了,2比1
It's a tie. That guy doesn't count. He can't even read.
是平局,那家伙不算,他都不识字
I know. He was just joking around.
我知道,他只是闹着玩的
Can you hang out here a little bit? I gotta go do something.
你等会好吗?我有点事
No problem.
没问题
Would you like
你想要来玩吗
We'll hop, hop, hop, hop
我们跳,跳,跳,跳
What do you say
你说什么
Get the door.
去开门
Hi, Julian. How you doing?
你好,Julian,你好吗?
I'm Scuba Sam.
我是 Scuba Sam
Scuba Steve's father.
Scuba Steve 的父亲
You see, my boy...
是这样,我的孩子
...needs to take a bath.
得洗个澡
The only problem is...
但问题是
...he's afraid to bathe alone.
他不敢一个人洗
So I was wondering...
所以我在想
...if maybe you could keep him company in the tub.
或许你可以在浴缸里陪他
Terrific.
太棒了
And after the bath, you have to try and study hard.
洗完澡后,你得好好学习
Because if you wanna be a member of the Scuba Squad, you have to be smart.
因为如果你想成为 Scuba 战队的成员 就必须很聪明
I could be in the Scuba Squad?
我能加入 Scuba 战队?
Well, sure. All you have to do is work hard.
嗯,当然,只要你好好学习
And don't tell a soul about the Scuba Squad...
还有,不要告诉任何人 关于 Scuba 战队的事情
...because then everybody will wanna join.
因为那样的话人人都要加入了
And one more thing...
还有一件事
...be nice to the delivery guy, would you?
对那个送外卖的好点,好吗?
It's not his fault he can't read.
他不识字不是他的错
Take care.
保重
He told me to watch his boat for him. Said that he wanted to...
他让我帮他看好飞船,说他要
...talk to you about some secret mission.
跟你谈谈秘密任务还是什么的
I have no idea what you're talking about.
我不知道你在说什么
How come I have to wear a bathing suit?
我为什么非得穿泳裤?
I don't know the rules...
我不知道有没有什么法规
...with little kids and grownups and being naked and just sit down.
限制大人和小孩裸体在一起,坐下
The good news is you're not smelling like a foot anymore.
好消息是你闻起来没有臭脚丫味儿了
I read something interesting. You know Benjamin Franklin invented...
我读到有趣的东西,你知道吗? 本杰明·富兰克林发明了
...bifocals? That's pretty cool.
两用眼镜?很酷吧
What are they?
是什么东西
I'll show you in that book. It might help you out with your school play.
我会给你看那本书,上面有很多有趣的 东西,或许对你学校的舞台剧有帮助
We'll make this a regular thing.
我们要把这当做每天的功课
Bathing and studying and eating right.
洗澡,学习还有吃东西
Put your head back. My grandmother did this to me.
仰头,我奶奶就是这样给我洗澡的
"Oh, boy. When I was a little girl, frankfurters only cost a nickel."
"哦,孩子,当我还是个小女孩的时候 香肠才卖5分钱"
Can you still have fun?
那我们还能玩吗?
Yeah, but after you study.
当然,不过要在你学习完后
In fact, we gotta get you dressing differently.
咱们还要穿不同的衣服
We'll go to Barney's.
等你出来,我们去 Barney's
Not that Barney. A more expensive Barney.
去 Barney?!不是那个 Barney 是个更贵的 Barney
All right, one at a time.
对,一次一张
That's one.
一张
Two.
两张
See? Urinals are good too.
怎么样?在小便池撒尿感觉也很好吧
" Electricity."
"电"
Very good.
很好
" Constitution."
"宪法"
That's it.
没错
" Philadelphia."
"费城"
Smart. Good.
聪明,好
" Fish"?
"鱼"?
" Pony"?
"小马"?
" Hip--"
"河…"(河马)
" Hiphop--"
"河里…"
" Hipopynonamous"?
"河豚鱼"?
Damn you! You gave him the easy ones!
该死的!你给他的都是简单的!
-Thanks! -You're welcome.
- 谢谢! - 不客气
Slow down.
慢点
You owe me a Sausage McMuffin.
你还欠我个汉堡
There's a pole there.
那儿有根杆子
My name is Alexander Hamilton.
我是亚历山大·汉密尔顿
I was the first secretary of the treasury.
我是第一任财政部长
I owned a bank and a newspaper.
拥有一家银行和一家报社
Aaron Bird shot me.
Aaron Bird 刺杀了我
Hi, my name is Benjamin Franklin.
Hi,我叫本杰明·富兰克林
I was a writer, a diplomat...
我是个作家,外交家
...an inventor and a statesman...
发明家和政治家
...although I only went to school for two years.
尽管我只上过两年学
I wrote many books and invented many things we still use today.
我写过很多书,还发明了很多 沿用至今的发明
The Declaration of lndependence is finished.
独立宣言完成了
Who will be the first to sign?
谁第一个签字?
-How about you, John Hancock? -I want to sign!
- 你怎么样,约翰·汉考克? - 我要签!
-Look at my man stand strong. -He's so cute.
- 看我的小男子汉站得多坚定 - 他真可爱
What are your cards?
你什么牌?
I got a six, a five, a jack, a four and a eight.
我有一个6,一个5,一个J,一个4和一个8
I win.
我赢了
What do you mean?
为什么你赢
I had a hand just like that. I didn't win.
我刚才也有这样一手牌,都没赢
Because I win.
因为我赢了
This is bullshit!
这真是胡扯!
All right. Take it easy, man.
行了,放松,哥们儿
Every time it's different cards.
每次他牌都不一样,都是他赢
So what? Relax. He's a kid.
那又怎么样?放松,他只是孩子
There should be same set of rules, no matter what age.
规则应该对每个人都一样 不管多大年龄
He's gotta learn how to lose too.
他也得学学什么是输
-Hello, Mr. Koufax. -Mr. Brooks, how you doing?
- 你好,Koufax 先生 - Brooks 先生,你好吗?
I was gonna give you a buzz.
我正打算给你电话的
You just called me Mr. Koufax, didn't you?
你刚才叫我 Koufax 先生,是吧?
It is your name, isn't it? Sonny Koufax?
是你的名字,没错吧? Sonny Koufax?
You held yourself out to be Kevin Gerrity...
你一直冒充 Kevin Gerrity
...to gain custody of young Julian.
来得到小 Julian 的抚养权
Big problem in this state.
这可是大问题了,Sonny
I've delivered to you before.
我给你送过外卖
You always order three pieces of cheesecake.
你总是要3块起司蛋糕
The real Kevin Gerrity asked me to take care of--
真的 Kevin Gerrity 让我来照顾…
Save it, Mr. Koufax.
省省吧,Koufax 先生
He has to come with me or I'll arrest you.
他现在得跟我走,否则我就逮捕你
Take out your handcuffs.
把你的手铐拿出来
I don't have any, but two policemen downstairs do.
我没有,但楼下的两个警察有
Listen, Sonny, I would like to help...
听着,Sonny,我想帮你的
...but my status in your country is not what you would call legal.
但我在你们这个国家的身份不合法
It's okay.
没关系
I'm Audi.
我走了
Julian, you're gonna have to come with me.
Julian,你必须跟我走
One second, pal.
等一下,伙计
Would you just give me a second to say goodbye to the kid?
能否给我一点时间跟孩子说再见?
Take a second.
就一会
You don't want me here anymore?
你不想让我继续留在这儿了?
No, that's not it, pal.
不,不是这样的
You just gotta go away for a little while.
你只是得离开一段时间
How long am I going away for?
我要离开多久?
I don't wanna lie to you.
我不想骗你
I don't think we're gonna...
我想我们不能
...be seeing each other anymore.
再见面了
I screwed up, pal. I'm so sorry.
我把事情弄糟了,很抱歉
Come here.
来
Put your coat on.
把外套穿上
It's not your fault, okay? I'm the idiot.
不是你的错,明白吗?我才是白痴
-I don't wanna go. -I know you don't.
- 我不想走 - 我知道你不想
But you have to, and you're gonna be okay.
但你必须走,你会很好的
Please don't make me go.
请不要让我走
I'm sorry, but I don't know what else to do.
对不起,但我不知道还能怎么办
I won't play the kangaroo song anymore.
我以后不再放袋鼠歌了
Come on.
来吧
Just go. You gotta go.
走吧,你必须走
You gotta go.
必须走
I don't wanna go. I promise...
我不走,我答应
...l'm sorry. I don't even like that song anymore.
对不起,我已经不喜欢那首歌了
I know, pal. That's not it.
我知道,不是因为那个
But I wipe my own ass! I wipe my own ass!
我自己擦屁股!我自己擦屁股!
I know.
我知道
-Layla, they took the kid. -Who?
- Layla,他们把孩子带走了 - 谁?
Social Services. I gotta get him back.
社会服务处,我得把他弄回来
You said this was just temporary.
什么意思,你说过这是临时的
I can't have it be temporary. It's gotta be permanent.
我知道,不能是临时的了 必须是永久
Okay, what can we do?
好的,我们能做什么?
I filed to get custody based on the child's best interests.
谁能取得孩子的抚养权 要依据孩子自己的兴趣
Tommy knew a clerk, so they fast-tracked the hearing. It's Tuesday.
Tommy 认识一个文员 打听到听证会是在周二
-This Tuesday? -You got work?
- 本周二? - 你得工作?
I gotta go to Washington for a hearing to dismiss my case.
我得去华盛顿参加我案子的听证会
Can you get somebody else?
可以让别人去吗?
I'm sorry, Sonny. I can't. It's my case.
很抱歉 Sonny，不能 这是我的案子
We don't even know where this kid's gonna end up.
那 Julian 的案子怎么办,我们甚至 不知道这孩子将来会在什么样的家庭
Sonny, this is exactly why I didn't wanna get involved.
Sonny,这正是我不想卷进来的原因
I had things going the way I wanted.
我本来过着自己想要的生活
Then at the park, you and this kid come barging into my life...
然后在公园,你和这孩子闯进了我的生活
...and it's screwing up everything I had planned.
而且打乱了我所有的计划
You think I planned on a kid showing up on my doorstep?
你认为我计划好了 有个孩子会出现在我门口?
But I fell in love with him.
但我爱上他了
So now my plans have changed.
所以现在我改变了我的机会
All rise.
全体起立
We're here to determine proper custody of Julian McGrath...
早上好,我们今天要决定 Julian McGrath
...also known as Julian Gerrity, a minor child.
也叫 Julian Gerrity 的抚养权
Representing New York City?
代表纽约市政府的是?
Ted Castellucci.
Ted Castellucci
Arthur Brooks, Social Services.
Arthur Brooks,社会服务处的
And representing Sonny Koufax?
代表 Sonny Koufax 的是?
Phillip D'Amato.
Phillip D'Amato
Thomas Grayton.
Thomas Grayton
Plus, I'll pretty much be representing myself.
另外,我代表我自己,法官大人
Anyone else?
还有吗?
Layla Maloney, Your Honour.
Layla Maloney,大人
Does this mean that you love me?
这是不是意味着你爱我?
Something like that.
差不多吧
First witness.
第一证人
Koufax is a good egg. He was nice to that kid.
Koufax 是个好人,他对那孩子很好
But he fights like a girl.
但他打架像个女孩
You like that?
这样说可以吧?
I'm right here, miss.
我就在这儿,小姐
What are you gonna do about it?
你要怎么样?
Are you drunk, Mr. Herlihy?
你喝醉了吗,Herlihy 先生?
I had a few chardonnays. What of it?
喝了一点白葡萄酒,能怎么样?
Get off the stand.
请下来吧
You got it.
好吧
I've got a few problems.
我还有点事
Off to a good start.
后面的会好点的
Mr. Koufax is a really cool guy. I wish my dad was as cool as him.
Koufax 先生是个真正的好人 我希望我爸也像他这么好
My dad was a military man.
我爸是个军人
Guess I wasn't such a "good soldier."
他料到我不会是个"好士兵"
When I was 35, he attempted to give me a crew cut while I was sleeping.
我35岁时,他试图在我睡着时 给我剃个军人式的平头
I broke his arm, haven't seen him since.
我醒了,打断了他的胳膊 从那以后就没再见过他
I'd rather live on the streets than under his rules.
我宁可睡马路也不愿受制于他
Anyway, I think Mr. Koufax should be acquitted of all the charges.
不管怎么说,我认为应该免除 Koufax 先生所有罪状
If O.J. can get away with murder, why can't Sonny have his kid?
OJ辛普森都能洗脱谋杀罪 Sonny 为什么不能得到那孩子呢?
This guy knows what I'm talking about.
这家伙知道我在说的什么意思
No more questions.
没有其它问题了
How long have you delivered food to Mr. Koufax?
你给 Koufax 先生送了多久外卖?
I deliver food for six years.
我送外卖6年了
Plus, I'm stripper. But I've put on weight so it's problem.
另外,我还是个舞男 但我长胖了,不行了
I see. And in your experience, was Sonny a good father to Julian?
知道了,在你看来 Sonny 是 Julian 的好父亲吗?
Oh, yes. They make terrific pair.
噢,是的,他们是很棒的一对父子
They went together like lamb and tuna fish.
他们在一起就像羊和金枪鱼
Lamb and tuna fish?
羊和金枪鱼?
Spaghetti and meatball? You more comfortable with that analogy?
通心粉和肉丸?这个比喻更好吧?
Yes, considering we're in America.
是的,因为我们是在美国
If you don't like spaghetti and meatballs, get out.
要是不喜欢通心粉和肉丸,趁早滚出去
I'll come give you a crew cut.
我要给你剃个平头
Let's see your clippers.
你的剪刀呢
Not my problem your dad was sick.
你爸有病又不是我的问题
Stop yelling at me!
别对我大叫!
Order! Order! Order!
秩序!秩序!秩序!
Am I in the right room?
请原谅,我来对地方了吗?
Who the hell are you?
你又是谁?
I'm Mr. Koufax's co-counsel.
我是 Koufax 先生的辩护律师
He has enough co-counsels.
他的辩护律师够多了
Well...
那么
...one more won't hurt.
再多一个也没什么
Let's get on with it.
我们继续,下个证人
Mr. Koufax is simply parading his buddies up there.
大人,上来的都是 Koufax 先生的朋友
Can't they find someone who isn't a friend?
不能找个不是他朋友的吗?
What were Julian and Mr. Koufax doing?
Julian 和 Koufax 先生当时在干什么?
Shopping.
购物
Did he appear to be an attentive, loving father?
他看上去是个关心爱护他的父亲吗?
He certainly did.
当然是
And how long have you disliked Mr. Koufax?
你讨厌 Koufax 先生多久了?
Since the day I met him.
自从我见到他
For the record, where did you work during medical school?
还有,你在进医学院前做什么工作?
Hooters.
舞女
No further questions.
没其它问题了
Asshole.
混蛋
Next witness.
下个证人
We'd like to call Julian McGrath.
大人,我们要叫 Julian McGrath 上庭
If it's okay with you, I'd like to ask you a few questions.
如果你愿意,我要问几个问题
This is just you and me talking...
这只是你和我之间的谈话
...so don't pay attention to these people.
所以不要在意下面那些人,好吗
Can you tell me how old you are?
能告诉我你几岁吗?
Your Honour, one second.
大人,请等一下
That's better, huh?
这样好点,是吧?
Can you tell me how old you are?
能告诉我你几岁吗?
Five.
5岁
What's your birthday?
你的生日呢?
July 1 5th.
7月15
Where were you born?
你在哪儿出生?
Toronto.
多伦多
Toronto? I thought you were from Buffalo.
多伦多?我以为你从水牛城来
I moved to Buffalo with my mommy.
我和妈妈搬到了水牛城
For the past six weeks, you've been living with Sonny?
过去6周,你都和 Sonny 一起住?
Did you and Sonny have fun?
你和 Sonny 一起开心吗?
What kind of things would you do?
你们都做些什么?
He taught me how to do the sleeper hold like Chief Jay Strongbow.
他教我摔角的绝招
That's nice.
真好
Anything else?
还有呢
He taught me how to pee on a building.
他教我怎样在墙角撒尿
Really?
真的?
And he taught me that Styx was one of the greatest American rock bands.
他还告诉我 Styx 是美国 最好的摇滚乐队之一
They only caught a bad rap...
他们只是运气不好
...because most critics are cynical assholes.
因为多数评论家都是玩世不恭的混蛋
I think we'd all agree with that.
我想大家都同意这点
Before you came here, do you remember the last thing your mommy said to you?
你来这里之前 记得妈妈最后跟你说的话吗?
That she loved me and I was gonna live with my new daddy.
她说她爱我并说我要跟我的新爸爸生活了
If your mother could pick anyone to be your new daddy...
如果你妈妈要给你选个新爸爸
...who would she pick?
她会选谁?
Sonny.
Sonny
Thank you, Julian.
谢谢你,Julian
You can step down now.
你可以下来了
That went good, don't you think?
进行得不错,你觉得呢?
I don't know. Judge doesn't look too happy.
不知道,法官看上去并不高兴
Mr. Koufax, anyone else?
Koufax 先生,还有其他人吗?
I'd like to call upon myself, Your Honour.
我想找我自己,大人
Awesome.
很好
Which of your esteemed co-counsels will examine you?
那么由哪位尊敬的律师来发问呢?
My father, Lenny Koufax.
我父亲,Lenny Koufax
What?
什么?
Forget it, Sonny.
得了吧,Sonny
What is going on?
怎么回事?
Nobody in this world thinks I shouldn't have a child more than that man.
大人,这世界上没人比他 更不希望我得到这孩子
He also happens to be a well-respected lawyer in Florida.
他正好也是佛罗里达一位有名的律师
If I can make a believer out of him, I can make a believer out of everybody.
如果我能让他信服 我就能让所有人信服
This court is after the truth, not the opinion of the defendant's father.
反对,法庭要的是事实 而不是被告父亲的意见
You want my opinion? My son is a moron.
你要我的意见?我儿子是个白痴
I withdraw my objection. Please proceed.
我撤回反对,请继续
This is a big mistake.
这是个大错误,Sonny
I only came today to make sure you didn't end up in jail.
我今天之所以来是不想你进监狱
That was nice of you. Thank you.
你真好,谢谢
To do what I think is right here.
只是来做我认为对的事
Cut your fingernails. They're too long.
该剪指甲了,太长了
Okay, Dad.
好的,爸
This case is simple.
大人,这案子很简单
It is absurd to think that Sonny Koufax is ready to raise a child.
认为 Sonny Koufax 能抚养小孩是荒谬的
-Objection! -Shut up, Tommy.
- 反对! - 闭嘴,Tommy
Sorry, Mr. Koufax.
对不起,Koufax 先生
First of all, how did...
首先,这个小男孩
...this sweet little boy, Julian, end up under your supervision?
Julian,是怎么样开始接受你监管的?
I told Social Services that my name was Kevin Gerrity.
我跟社会服务处说我叫 Kevin Gerrity
-Of course, you are not Kevin Gerrity. -No.
- 当然,你不是 Kevin Gerrity - 不是
-So you lied. -Yes.
- 所以你在撒谎 - 是的
Like the time I found a bag of pot in your drawer...
就像以前我在你内衣抽屉里发现一包大麻
...and you said you thought they were pencil shavings.
你说你以为那是铅笔屑
Remember when I told you Aunt Fay was coming to New York...
记得我上次打电话 告诉你 Fay 姨妈要来纽约
...and I wanted you to show her the city?
我想让你带她在市里逛逛?
And you said that you had better things to do.
但你说你有更重要的事
That's right.
对
I'm curious. Just what were those better things that you had to do?
我很好奇,是什么重要的事呢?
Jethro Tull had a reunion concert in New Jersey, so I caught that.
Jethro Tull 在新泽西举办复出演唱会 所以我得去
What happened to Aunt Fay that weekend?
那么 Fay 姨妈后来发生了什么?
She died.
死了
Yes, she did.
对,她死了
Did you happen to make it to her funeral?
你后来去参加她的葬礼了吗?
Why not?
为什么没去?
I went to Jones Beach, got drunk and fell asleep.
我去海滩玩,喝多睡着了
Hell, yes!
真有你的!
Some role model.
真是个好榜样
Your Honour...
法官大人
...my son doesn't have health insurance.
我儿子没有医疗保险
He doesn't know how to boil an egg.
他不会煮鸡蛋
He filed for social security at the age of 30.
30岁才申请社保
He is a drain on the economy, on the country...
他依赖于经济,依赖于国家
...and most of all, on me!
还依赖于我!
Your Honour...
法官大人
...to give this young man...
把一个人的抚养权交给
...custody over another life is not only wrong...
这个年轻人不仅是个错误
...it's insane.
简直是疯了
I love you.
我爱你
What?
什么?
Don't be scared. It's all right.
不用担心,没什么
I'm not scared.
我可没担心
If I get custody of Julian, I'll be his father forever.
如果得到 Julian 的抚养权 我就永远是他父亲了
That scares you because you think there's a good chance I'll fail.
你担心我很可能失败
Sonny, it's more than a chance. It's a certainty.
Sonny,不是可能,而是肯定
You're wrong, Dad.
你错了,老爸
You can be scared that I might get pickpocketed in a bad neighbourhood...
如果我在治安不好的地方被偷了钱包
...or break my legs skiing.
或者滑雪时摔断了腿,你可以担心
But don't be scared about me being a dad, because I will not fail.
但是不要担心我当不好这个爸爸 因为我不可能失败
I love this kid too much.
我太爱这孩子了
I love him as much as you love me, Dad.
我像你爱我一样爱他,老爸
I'm gonna give him advice and I'm gonna guide him...
我会给他建议,引导他
...and I'll be there whenever he needs me.
在他需要我的时候帮他
I'll fly to New York to be at his court case...
我会为了他的庭审飞到纽约
...even if I disagree with why he's there.
哪怕我起初不认同他的做法
But, Sonny, you work in a tollbooth.
但是,Sonny,你在收费站工作
Don't worry about money.
别担心钱
I am in love with a beautiful girl who makes plenty of it.
我爱上了一个能赚不少钱的漂亮姑娘
She'll be my sugar mama.
她是我的小富婆
I gotta get me one of those.
我应该也找一个
I know this is the right thing because I would die for this kid...
我认为这是我该做的 因为我可以为这孩子献出生命
...just so he won't feel one ounce of sadness.
只要他能过的快乐
That's why you're here right now, to protect me, to be scared for me...
这也正是你来这里的原因 来保护我,来关心我
...to be a good father.
来当个好父亲
And that's exactly what I'm gonna be.
我也想像你一样
Hello, Dad?
你好,爸爸吗?
Yeah, I just wanted to say I love you.
对,我就是想说我爱你
Hi, Mom? Could you put Dad on the phone for a second?
Hi,妈妈?能让爸爸接一下电话吗?
Can I borrow that when you're done?
你打完能借我吗?
Your Honour...
法官大人
...my son deserves this kid.
我儿子应该得到抚养权
I love you too, sir.
我也爱你,长官
Mr. Koufax...
Koufax 先生
...the fact is you kidnapped this child.
但事实是你绑架了这孩子
Not only shouldn't you get custody...
你不仅不该得到抚养权
...but since you obtained him by defrauding the state...
而且由于你通过欺骗政府得到他
...you should be in jail.
你应该入狱
Bailiff, remand him until I can figure out the punishment.
法警,在我宣判之前先把他押下去
Wait. You can't take him away.
等等,你不能带走他
As that boy's father, I refuse to press charges.
作为孩子的父亲,我拒绝起诉
Oh, God. Corinne, I'm sorry.
噢,老天,Corinne,对不起
Six years ago, Joe Carter....
6年前,Joe Carter
Joe Carter?
Joe Carter?
Toronto and the Phillies. World Series.
多伦多对费城,职业棒球赛
Mitch Williams-- We flew up for the night.
Mitch Williams… 我们那晚专程飞去看比赛
There was a girl.
有个女孩
Oh, God.
哦,老天
I'm an idiot. I was so hammered.
我当时很傻很天真
Chicken wings, Molson 3-0. Canadian beer is like moonshine.
美味的鸡翅,Molson 队3:0获胜 加拿大啤酒又像月光一样醉人
Hell, yes.
对极了
You remember? It was at that Toronto Hooters.
想起来了?是在多伦多的 Hooters 餐厅
That was before he met you. That Hooters thing is a coincidence.
那时他还没遇见你 Hooters 餐厅只是个巧合
I'm sorry, Corinne.
对不起,Corinne
I know this changes everything, but I had to do the right thing.
我知道这让会让一切都改变 但我现在必须这样做
Mr. Castellucci.
Castellucci 先生
Pending a blood test, l....
看验血结果吧
Whatever.
随便
The court grants custody to Kevin Gerrity, pending the DNA test results.
本庭核准 Kevin Gerrity 的抚养权 取决于DNA检验结果
I want you to be my dad, Sonny.
我要你当我爸爸,Sonny
I know. I do too, pal.
我知道,我也是
But I'm not sure that can happen exactly the way we want it.
但我不能保证事情能像我们希望的那样
Because it seems you already have a daddy.
因为你似乎已经有个爸爸了
But I'll tell you what I can do.
不过我告诉你我的想法
I can be your friend, no matter what. All right?
我可以做你的朋友,无论发生什么 好吗?
I'll always be your friend.
我永远是你的朋友
I'll always be your family. I'll always be around.
永远是你的家人,永远在你身边
I promise.
我保证
The kid's good at tying his shoes.
这孩子系鞋带还不赖
He's not great at it, so work with him.
但还不算太好,得好好教他
-I'll teach him bunny ears. -What's bunny ears?
- 我会教他打蝴蝶结 - 什么蝴蝶结?
Make bunny ears, cross and pull them through.
蝴蝶结啊,交叉,然后拉过去
I go with this loop, swoop and pull thing. He likes that.
我教的是绕,穿,拉,他喜欢那样
-I don't know that. -Go with the loop, swoop and pull.
- 我不知道 - 还是绕,穿,拉吧
I swear to God it's working.
我发誓那样好
All right.
好吧
Go with the bunny ears thing. You're his dad, right? I'm sorry.
还是打蝴蝶结吧 你才是他爸爸,对吧,对不起
It's important, when you eat at my restaurant...
这很重要,你在我的餐馆吃饭的时候
...you never order BLT.
绝不要点 BLT
You must trust me. Stay away from BLT, okay?
你要相信我,别点 BLT,好吗?
Hey, guys.
嘿,你们好
I'm gonna leave you with your dad now, Julian.
要把你交给你爸爸了,Julian
He's a good man. I've known him my whole life.
他是个好人,是我一辈子的朋友
So you two have fun and I'll see you in the morning.
你们俩好好玩 我们明天早上一起吃早饭
All right?
好吧?
-Quit scaring the kid for a minute. -Who am I scaring?
- 别再吓唬孩子了 - 我吓唬谁了?
Bye, pal.
再见,伙计
I went to China. Do you know where that is?
我之前去了中国,你知道是哪里吗?
It's in Asia, which is...
他在亚洲,靠着…
...by Europe. I brought some cool stuff back.
欧洲,我买回来一些很酷的东西
Did you move the bench?
是你动了椅子吗?
That's pretty funny.
很有趣吧
You know what I got? Some noisemakers. Check this out.
知道我带了什么?摔炮,看
Wanna try one?
要试试吗?
That's my foot!
我的脚!
You're nice man.
你是好人
I've got Spice Channel. It's blurry but it's nice.
我订了个新频道,挺聒噪,但还不错
Let's make this quick. I gotta get to work.
(1年3个月零6天后) 我们快点,我还得上班呢
Holy shit. Sonny Koufax would rather work than eat.
见鬼了,Sonny Koufax 宁可工作也不吃饭了
I'm working on a big case. I gotta sue you for making me come here.
在忙一个大案子 我要告你们带我来这儿
Surprise!
惊喜!
Did you just waste the good surprise on me again?
你们是不是又把好惊喜浪费在我身上了?
Hi, Corinne.
Hi,Corinne
-Happy birthday. -Thanks, everybody.
- 生日快乐 - 谢谢,各位
Hey, you guys. How are you?
嘿,你们好啊
Happy birthday, Daddy.
生日快乐,老爸
How you doing, cutie?
你好吗,小可爱?
Sonny, I beat you so bad in basketball yesterday.
Sonny,昨天打篮球我可赢了你
From now on, I have to stop letting you win.
从现在起,我不会让你赢了
I stopped that months ago. He still wins.
几个月前我就不想让他赢了 他还是赢
That's because you suck.
那是因为你太菜
Corinne, put a tank top on for old time's sake.
Corinne,看在以前的份上 穿上那小背心吧
-What is he talking about, Mommy? -Nothing.
- 他在说什么,妈妈? - 没什么
-Happy birthday, Sonny. -Thank you.
- 生日快乐,Sonny - 谢谢
It's a clock radio.
是个闹钟收音机
-Thanks for telling me. -I have to split.
- 谢谢告诉我 - 我得走了
I got deliveries.
还有外卖要送
Hang out with us. We'll have fun.
和我们玩吧,会很开心的
No, I can't stay. I'll hang for a little bit.
不,我不能呆在这儿 我还是呆一会儿吧
There you go. Come on, let's eat, everybody.
随你,来吧,用餐吧,各位
Hey, you! Still missing that tooth, huh?
嘿,是你!还想念那颗牙吧?
Can we get some fries?
给我们些炸鸡好吗?
Vanessa.
Vanessa
You're a Hooters girl?
你现在是个舞女?
What happened to Sid's five-year plan?
Sid 的5年计划怎么样了?
How you doing?
你怎么样?
-Maybe it's a 1 0-year plan. -Is that the guy with the old balls?
- 或许是个10年计划 - 是那个长老蛋蛋的家伙吗?
I think it is.
我想是的
Come on. I bet they're nice.
来吧,我打赌它们很好
You're not supposed to say " balls." Testicles.
你不该说"蛋蛋",是睾丸